...number 49 bound for Nishi-Otani...
Nationwide Railway Timetable
Can I catch up to her?
And if I do catch up to her, what the heck do I say to her?
I-I'm lonely!
Do I have the right to stop Misaki?
Liar!
Sir, are you going sightseeing, at this time of night?
It's pitch-dark; you won't be able to see anything.
Uh, no, I'm meeting a friend.
On that promontory?
Son, you're not by any chance...
Well, the construction's done, so I guess there's nothing to worry about.
Huh?
Tip of the Promontory.
You have only that one life.
Don't throw it away.
Did I pass her up somewhere?
Or else... she couldn't have already...
Calm down...
I know what train Misaki took from the timetable she left in the hospital.
I shelled out for a limited express train to chase her; there's no way I'm not in time.
If you have the courage to jump, have the courage to live.
Why?
Why what?
Was I overconfident in guessing she'd come here?
No, you weren't.
But Misaki, you're...
I'm right here.
Huh?!
The time you arrived was only five minutes apart from when I did.
You could become a detective, Sato.
I didn't know what to do because you weren't saying anything.
Well, shall we go home? It's cold here and all.
I don't want to.
What?
If you have the courage to jump, have the courage to live.
You can't die! Let's live on!
This is no joke! Thanks to you, the money I worked so hard for is blown!
I'm sorry.
Huh?
It would've been better if I'd died yesterday as planned.
It's just like my stepfather said.
When I'm around, everybody meets with misfortune.
My mother dying was also my fault. My original father dying probably was too.
My stepfather tried his hardest to get rid of me, but he failed and, predictably, his luck went bad.
Once I started helping my aunt, her recruiting stopped going well,
and she started fighting a lot with my uncle.
All of that was my fault.
I'm a worthless human being who summons misfortunes.
I'm a person this world doesn't need.
But I didn't want to admit that. That's why I planned your project.
If just one single person needed me, my stepfather's words would have been proven wrong.
It would be okay for me to be alive.
But that project ended in failure.
I'm not needed even by you, Sato.
There's no point in my being alive.
And so you pulled that "New Year's grated yams" crap?
Gimme a break!
That stunt was just like saying, "Come after me!"
I didn't think you'd find me.
That's why, when I saw you just now, I thought my heart was going to stop.
It would've been fine if it had stopped though.
What's more, you know, a final note is important.
If there's no note, it's trouble for the people you leave behind,
not knowing whether it was a suicide or not.
Like what happened with my mother...
Give this up. I'm begging you!
There'll be good things too, if you're alive.
Your uncle and your aunt and such would grieve!
I need you... That's it, Misaki!
I like you! I love you! Please, don't die!
You say funny things, Sato.
But it won't work.
Because I am going to die.
So, it's useless after all?
I don't have any words to hold Misaki back.
And besides, what's wrong with her dying?
It's all the same. The only difference is whether it happens early or late.
It's just like Misaki said before.
Even to live into the future will just mean misery, with nothing but painful things.
It's meaningless.
Being alive is meaningless.
Dying is better.
But...
But, you know...
But you can't, absolutely not.
Don't go saying you're going to die!
Goodbye, Sato.
My imagination is poor,
so I can't make myself believe in God as well as other people do.
All he would have to do is cause a really flashy miracle,
like in the Bible or something, right before my eyes.
And if only I could believe,
I could blame all the bad things on God.
It's not your fault, Misaki.
It's not your fault, not even a little.
There are others who are to blame.
Others who have made you suffer, Misaki.
That's right. Where lies the reason why Misaki suffers?
If Misaki is always hurting and lonely, so that she can't go on, that's an abomination.
So, it means there exists a source of that evil.
There's someone evil who's making Misaki suffer.
You know something? There are conspiracies in this world.
But ninety-nine percent of all so-called "conspiracies" are simply imagination.
Or they're just big lies.
So, one percent of it is the truth?
That's it, Misaki.
Somebody has, against extreme odds, become aware of a genuine conspiracy.
Huh?
And who is that?
It's me, Tatsuhiro Sato.
And the enemy's name is...
I've known the name since long ago.
The evil organization that makes us suffer.
Yes, their name is...
The N.H.K.
N.H.K.?
That's right.
Their name is the N.H.K.,
a secret society that covers all the world.
The misfortune that occurs around you is all the work of the N.H.K.!
Sato, what are you say...
Sato?
It's a mental assault from the N.H.K.!
I've told the organization's secret to you, Misaki, so they've come to do away with me!
What? What is this N.H.K.?
The Japan Social-Withdrawal Association!
The evil secret society that turned me into a hikikomori.
Or the Japan Frailty Association!
They went after Senpai's frail heart,
and drove her to participate in the offline meeting!
The wicked hand of an N.H.K. is also reaching for you, Misaki!
That one is the Japan Pessimism Association!
It's them and only them who have driven you, Misaki, into thinking negatively about everything!
All the misfortunes that happen in the world are conspiracies by the N.H.K.!
They're not your fault, Misaki!
If you don't like the name N.H.K., call it whatever you like.
God, for instance.
God?
Yes, he's come at last to finish me off.
You can see him too, can't you, Misaki?
He's right there!
I can't see anything like that!
You can! Focus your eyes well and look!
I can't! I can't see him!
You can! I'm absolutely sure you can!
That's the source of all evil!
The last boss!
It's too late for me.
But I won't go without a fight!
I'm dragging him down with me!
Look, Misaki!
This is the one and only item that can defeat him:
The Revolution Bomb!
That's right.
Using this is the only way to defeat that thing!
The only way is to throw myself into a kamikaze attack!
I'll guard your life, Misaki!
Sato!
Goodbye, Misaki!
Thanks for everything up till now!
Live in good health in the future! And lead a happy life for me!
That is my final request!
So, Misaki, live on for me.
I'm an idiot, huh?
I'm truly an idiot.
To think that this kind of thing is the only way that comes to mind to secure the life of a girl I like...
What an idiot, truly an idiot. Idiot!
Huh?
"A girl I like?"
What, then? I actually was in love with Misaki.
A dramatic death just isn't fitting for us.
I'll show you, Yamazaki!
I'm about to die for Misaki, the girl I love!
It's the ultimate in "dramatic," don't you think?!
...the construction's done...
"Construction"?
Sato!
What's this all about?!
Well, the construction's done, so I guess there's nothing to worry about.
So, they intend to keep me from dying dramatically at any price?!
This is cheating!
Don't look! What are you crying about? I'm the one who feels like crying!
You can't die.
Don't you dare.
If it took almost an hour by taxi, that means...
If we walk to the station, it will take till morning.
No Signal
So, as things stand, in the end we're gonna freeze to death.
There's an abandoned house nearby though.
An abandoned house?
My house.
Apparently, it's the house my original father built.
He gave me my name too.
"Because Ishihama Misaki promontory is nearby," he said. Pretty random, huh?
This was my room. I was using it until my third year of middle school.
You're the first person outside my family who's ever come in here, Sato.
Because my stepfather got angry if I brought friends home.
It's warmer this way.
Now you tell me something about yourself too, Sato.
What?
Anything is fine.
I'll listen, no matter how boring it is.
Well then, I'll tell about a dream I had this morning.
Sure...
A jet-black snake came out of the sea,
and started blasting away with a gun glowing with black light.
Then with a long, thick sword...
Enough!
The penalty for sexual harassment is a million yen!
All right, I know.
Then should I talk about my childhood or something?
Yeah...
Well, when I was a kid, I used to play baseball and stuff a lot at a park near my house.
Well, maybe you'd call it baseball, what with using a rubber ball and a plastic bat...
Sato, it's possible I'll be getting married in the near future.
Since I came back here,
my parents have been bugging me to have arranged marriage meetings.
What could I do? So, just once I met someone, for their sakes.
And I unexpectedly hit the jackpot!
Apparently she liked me too, and by now we're nuts about each other!
Sato, are you keeping healthy in your hikikomori state?
My baby was born without incident.
Our home is a mansion.
My life is moving forward under full sail.
Unbelievable, everybody I know...
No, I don't wanna go! What a pain!
No, I can't! I can't, I can't!
Well, make the best of things, all you guys.
I plan to get along too, however I can, to keep hanging in there the best I can.
Thanks for your patronage!
Beware of Molesters.
You're late! How many times have I said, "Come right away after you eat dinner."
I did just finish dinner!
And are you in some elevated position to order me around?
It's just that my aunt and uncle feel at ease while I'm spending time with you.
So, what about the homework?
Here...
Good.
It's humiliating, somehow, to be learning subjects from you.
You dropped out of high school. I dropped out of college.
Anybody could see which of us is the more accomplished.
You think so?
I swear I'm gonna pass the test to enter a better college than you went to.
Oh, that's right, I forgot.
I thought of what it is, my N.H.K.
Huh?
By means of your actions, the evil god has perished.
But we can't be sure that evil won't ever revive itself.
That being the case...
The "Japan Hostage Exchange Association?!"
Each member offers their life as a hostage to the other.
In short, it says "If you die, I'll die too, you scoundrel!"
If we do that, just like the faceoff between nuclear powers during the Cold War,
even if one wants to die, they won't be able to.
In the end,
not a single one of our problems has been solved.
From here on, too, we'll probably be whispering "I can't, I can't" every day while we go on living.
But still... Yeah!
I don't know how long it will hold up,
but I'll give it a try as best I can.
Tatsuhiro Sato
Misaki Nakahara
With this, I'm sure both you and I will be okay, Sato.
Welcome to the N.H.K.!
Final Episode
Even if this world
moshimo ashita kono sekai ga
were to end tomorrow, since it's you,
owaru to shite mo kimi no koto dakara
would you take the curt attitude of
sore nara sore demo iika
"If so, that's okay with me"?
sokkenai taido toru no kana
There's no need to strain yourself.
muri suru koto wa dakedo
Just sometimes would be fine, so lift up your face
tama ni demo iikara kao wo agete
and look this way.
kocchi wo miteyo
Look at me.
watashi wo mite
Though it's a tiny world,
chippoke na sekai nanoni
for some reason it's too big for these two hands.
naze darou kono ryoute ni wa ooki sugiru
Though it's an endless world,
hateshinai sekai nanoni
for some reason it's too small for these two hands.
naze darou kono ryoute ni wa chiisa sugiru
Hey,
nee modokashii
in the brilliant morning light
asa no hikari no naka de
I want to laugh with you.
kimi to warai tai