I lift my eyes a little and look into the sky
sukoshi miageta sora
All I do is mutter every time,
dekisugita nichijou
as I turn my back
se wo mukeru tabi ni
on this perfect everyday life
tsubuyaku dake
"Where am I supposed to go?"
doko ni ikeba ii no
With you who are giving me a look like that?
sonna kao shiteru kimi to
In the shadows of a back alley,
rojiura no kage tokei no hari ga
the hands of a clock repaint the time that has been stopped.
tomatta jikan wo nurikaete
Extended hands,
sashinobeta ryoute
puzzle pieces that don't fit.
kamiawanai pazuru wo
Until the abandoned two
okizari ni shiteta
reunite with something
futari deau made
that has been lost.
nakushiteta nanika
Recover
saigo no kakera wo
the last piece,
torimodoshite
and let's start walking.
arukidasou
Because of you guys, we didn't have time to eat anything, you see.
Mm, this goes down pretty smooth, huh?
The Island Nearest to Paradise
August 11, 2006, 11:00 AM.
And I was thinking there was no other possible way.
So was I.
When a person gets caught up in one notion, he becomes unable to think of anything else,
even though, in fact, another way of resolving things is often right before his eyes.
If we hadn't had that damned campfire,
we might have dragged ourselves right up there and done it.
Yeah...
We have to be grateful to him.
Umm...
It's good you didn't die, huh?
You...
Don't!
Please...
Please stop...
I was more scared than that!
Why is it that at times like this I'm not plagued by lethargy?
I'd like to just sleep, without thinking about anything.
Huh?
What's that all about?
He looks like he's from an inn.
Would you be the group from the "Island Nearest to Paradise" offline meeting?
How does he know about us?
I put a call in.
We're all tired, aren't we?
We can take a hot spring bath and relax a bit before we go.
Jogasaki...
Well, now, right this way please!
Shall we take him up on this offer?
I guess so.
Well, come along, Miss.
What? No, I'm not going.
Really? You're not with them?
Jogasaki...
I'll be there as soon as I return the boat.
Welcome!
Your names and addresses, please.
Right...
Guest Register
That was an unbelievable day, huh?
Yes...
At this time yesterday, we'd all given up hope about everything in this world,
and now we're here soaking in a hot spring, huh?
Are you the ones?
The fools who were going to cast away your lives?
"Fools," you say?
Yes, fools.
Selfishly throwing away the life his parents gave him is something a fool does.
If you actually were dead now, you'd be beyond all salvation.
Hey!
Things are a little better anyway, since you came back alive.
If you guys hadn't come back safely, what do you think would've happened?
The marina staff would all have been sent out as search crews.
In the worst case, the people from the fisheries cooperative might have gotten dragged in too.
The inns hereabouts would've fallen behind in their work with all the inquiries and whatnot.
If your bodies had washed up, that would've been big news too.
Worst case, if they'd drifted up near the inns, it'd have an impact on the lodge businesses here too.
It'd be huge trouble all around.
Well? Now do you see the idiocy of fools who would throw away their lives and cause trouble to others
just because of their own situations?
If you do understand, then don't ever think up anything so stupid again.
This is a warning from somebody who was a fool himself long ago.
Hana-Hana's running late, huh?
Women's baths take a long time, you know.
There's nothing for it. Shall we start without her?
Huh? I'm sure that's...
That's my car.
I had that young man Jogasaki go get it for me.
What? Senpai?
You were out for a drive?
Just a bit. It's such a nice car, I couldn't help it.
Women really are tougher than men.
Mr. Nomura, Mr. Kusano, members of your family are here.
Hidehito!
You don't have to worry about the clinic!
Just leave it to your father!
All this because you can't become a doctor...
Mother...
I was wrong.
Yuu!
How could you do something so stupid?!
The fault is all mine.
There's no excuse for what I did.
And you! Dragging our son into this...
Stop it, Dad!
I'm to blame.
It's because I'm such a wimp.
To have my mother cry at me like that is too much. I got worn out and escaped.
Coming from me, it doesn't mean much, but it is wrong to want to die.
After all this, I talked to my mother for the first time in a long time, and I finally understood.
As long as there's someone who'll grieve, it's wrong to want to die.
Uh, excuse me...
Sato, this is for you, if you're interested.
What's this?
It's a free pass to "Ultimate Fantasy," an online game.
If you type in this number, you can play for the first month for free.
You're a hikikomori, right, Sato?
A person I met online is also a hikikomori, and he's making a ton of money off of this game.
What? Off of a game?
How?
He does R.M.T.: "Real Money Trading."
He trades items and gold he acquires in the game for real money.
Amazing, huh?
Wow...
With this, even if you're shut inside your house, you can earn money.
It's perfect for you, Sato.
"Vina Teelo"...
Thank you, I'll give it a try.
See you in Vina Teelo.
Well, I'm off.
Now you can't die at least until you meet him inside the game.
Hidehito! Hidehito!
I'm going to head out too.
We probably won't meet again, but take care.
You too.
Hidehito, where are you?
I'm over here. Don't yell like that!
You're back, huh?
Let's get going soon.
Uh, right.
Uh, are...
Huh?
Yamazaki and the...
Yamazaki said he had something important to do;
he left a little while ago.
Something important to do?
Sample!
What's that?
Why do you charge 3,000 yen for a trial version?
Is he crazy or what?
So, he's saying the Comic Stall is more important than I am?
And about that girl...
Huh?
She just vanished at some point; I think she probably went home.
I wasn't really concerned about her.
Thank you.
Won't you ride back in my car?
What?
No, I'm in the mood to go home by myself.
I see.
Well, once things settle down, let's get together in Tokyo to eat or something.
Sure.
Let's go, Hitomi.
Sato...
I'm truly sorry I got you caught up in this kind of thing.
It's all right. Don't worry about it.
I wish you happiness, Senpai.
I'll give you a ride to the station.
Thanks.
Makoto!
Dad...
What are you doing here?
Mom told me to come meet you here.
She said let's all give it another try.
Misaki Nakahara
You're a hikikomori, more pathetic than a stray dog!
...so much more of a throwaway hunk of refuse than me!
So... You can't die! Absolutely not!
I don't get her at all.
Sato!
Are you alive, Sato?
Damn it, I didn't think the Comic Stall customers would all be jerks!
Learn to read things' auras!
Don't they even realize that once it's completed it's going to be a big-name item?
What hurt us is that we didn't get to go on the first day.
Games weren't the main items today.
It's your fault, Sato.
I don't care how much you despaired about your hikikomori life;
there was no reason to stir up so much crap on the day of Comic Stall!
The idiots in my class are giving me cold glares too; I've had enough!
I'll be waiting at the usual place, at the usual time.
I'll be waiting
Sato...
Are you listening to me?
Yeah...
Won't you come with me to see the fireworks?
I think positive things would come out of it.
If we're together, I'm sure you'll be fine.
Damn! If it were at least finished,
those idiots would understand at least a little how wonderful our game is!
Sato, where are you going?
I'm here.
This is a copy of the contract.
These past few days, you skipped counseling without permission.
That's a complete violation of this contract.
"I'll be collecting that fine of one million yen."
Hey! You were...
Is what I could say.
But I was also keeping my house a secret from you.
I feel a little guilty about that. I'm sorry.
As a result, I'll dispense with the fine this time.
Starting tomorrow, we'll do counseling as we did previously,
but you absolutely must come.
Who are you to decide things for me?
I'm glad you came back for me, Sato.
Welcome home.
Glad to be home.
Huh? Who's that?
Hello?
Hello? Tatsuhiro?
Yeah. Mom, what's the matter?
I wanted to talk to you a little bit.
That's sure a gloomy voice.
I wonder if she heard something about the offline meeting?
What's with the gloomy voice? That's not like you, Mom.
I'm feeling really well on my end.
Is that right?
What's this? So, it's not about the offline meeting?
Tatsuhiro? Stay calm and listen, okay?
Sure.
The truth is, I'm sorry, but...
Huh? I can't hear you very well.
What?
That's... It can't be!
Episode 14
Welcome to Reality!
You're joking, right, Mom?
Even if this world
moshimo ashita kono sekai ga
were to end tomorrow, since it's you,
owaru to shite mo kimi no koto dakara
would you take the curt attitude of
sore nara sore demo iika
"If so, that's okay with me"?
sokkenai taido toru no kana
There's no need to strain yourself.
muri suru koto wa dakedo
Just sometimes would be fine, so lift up your face
tama ni demo iikara kao wo agete
and look this way.
kocchi wo miteyo
Look at me.
watashi wo mite
Though it's a tiny world,
chippoke na sekai nanoni
for some reason it's too big for these two hands.
naze darou kono ryoute ni wa ooki sugiru
Though it's an endless world,
hateshinai sekai nanoni
for some reason it's too small for these two hands.
naze darou kono ryoute ni wa chiisa sugiru
Hey,
nee modokashii
in the brilliant morning light
asa no hikari no naka de
I want to laugh with you.
kimi to warai tai
You gather companions and adventure together.
You work too!
I owe this to you too.
Next episode, "Welcome to the Fantasy!"
Next Episode
Welcome to the Fantasy!