I lift my eyes a little and look into the sky
sukoshi miageta sora
All I do is mutter every time,
dekisugita nichijou
as I turn my back
se wo mukeru tabi ni
on this perfect everyday life
tsubuyaku dake
"Where am I supposed to go?"
doko ni ikeba ii no
With you who are giving me a look like that?
sonna kao shiteru kimi to
In the shadows of a back alley,
rojiura no kage tokei no hari ga
the hands of a clock repaint the time that has been stopped.
tomatta jikan wo nurikaete
Extended hands,
sashinobeta ryoute
puzzle pieces that don't fit.
kamiawanai pazuru wo
Until the abandoned two
okizari ni shiteta
reunite with something
futari deau made
that has been lost.
nakushiteta nanika
Recover
saigo no kakera wo
the last piece,
torimodoshite
and let's start walking.
arukidasou
Kokogi Designer Institute
Summer vacation starts tomorrow!
Wanna go somewhere?
Summer Vacation
...my script for the summer Comic Stall!
Umm...
Tomorrow I can't.
I have an audition for a TV anime that starts in the fall.
They said it'll be late night by the time we finish, so I don't think I can make it.
Oh, is that right?
Ask me again sometime.
I'll make time for you, I promise.
Okay, next time then.
I'm sorry.
Sorry for the wait!
Hey, Nanako, what part are you reading for?
Suzuran, the magical ninja girl!
You seem pretty confident!
I've got the script down to a "T."
Sorry, tomorrow I can't.
Stab.
Get lost, villains!
Summer Vacation
...so anyway, we're gonna talk about Jung today.
Jung had a disagreement with Freud, apparently, and went in another direction.
Jung apparently had a very hard time establishing his ideas.
We're alone in the park at night...
Then at last he published his theories of psychological types.
...in spite of what happened.
Is she fine with that?
On the basis of these cases...
my conclusion is that you are an "Introverted Feeling" type.
You are frightened of the "Great Mother."
You are also fighting against your "Shadow."
Didn't we cover that topic before?
What? Did... did we?
Yeah.
Let's stop here for today.
Your heart doesn't seem to be in it anyway.
That's you, isn't it?
Well then, see you tomorrow.
Get it together, Tatsuhiro Sato.
My instincts are telling me that to get too close to her is dangerous.
I still don't know anything about her:
Who she really is, or what her real purpose is either.
She may be a secret operative of the Nihon Hikikomori Kyoukai!
We'll give it a try.
Everyone's doing it.
Come on, Sato, let's...
Is this all right?
Can I really do this?
Sato! Sato!
I'm coming in, Sato!
Yay!
Yamazaki?
You're hiding away in here as always, huh?
You've been drinking, huh?
Am I not supposed to? I'm over 20!
By law, I'm allowed to consume alcohol!
Here's to the law: Banzai!
Drunks are a pain in the...
Sato, the rest of the world is on summer vacation already!
This is no time to be casually shutting yourself in!
Let's go to the beach! To the beach!
The beach?
Sato!
Damn! Her face is in my mind for everything!
Yamazaki...
The fact is I don't have swim trunks.
So, I can't do the beach.
What are you saying, Sato?
You don't need swim trunks or anything to go to the beach!
What?
For healthy young folk like us, summer at the beach can only mean one thing:
The Summer Comic Stall!
Summer Comic Stall?
Comic Stall Venue
I see, it's the ocean; I'll give you that.
I'd heard about a huge doujin sales exhibition during the summer and winter.
So, they hold it in this kind of place, huh?
Some people in my class got a booth at the Comic Stall.
This is it.
Wow...
But we got to talking about how lame it would be if we only have one game to put out.
With only a third-rate game like that, there's no way any customers or anybody will come!
A game is a holistic work of art.
To try to fake it by filling up holes in the game script with minigames along the way is too damn cynical!
Who the hell invited Yamazaki?
Do you think like that?!
It's the last drinking party of first term.
You're all really too optimistic!
We were supposed to at least try to invite everybody.
Your thinking is way too optimistic!
I figured, even if I invited him, he wouldn't come.
Do you hear me, all of you?
It's all really about how good a script you create!
I mean, he hasn't ever come to anything before.
If the most crucial thing, the story, is lame, the players won't bite!
Don't you get even this most basic concept?
If that's the case, can you make a more interesting one?!
I can.
Or should I say I'm in the middle of making one with an old friend.
In high school he was head of the Literature Club,
so the script is flawless!
Really?!
If you're interested,
shall I do you the honor of setting it out at your booth?
I'll teach you what a real game is!
My classmates were in tears, begging for it.
So I decided to put our game in their booth.
So... Hey!
We've got less than a month!
Without a deadline, you'd just laze around and procrastinate, right?!
Anyway, Sato, you know you're the one who started this talk of creating a game!
You want to be a game creator, right?
You're right.
Once my buzz wears off, we'll get to work immediately.
We've only been given one month after all.
Yeah...
Use that laptop.
Let's watch each other as we work to keep us from procrastinating.
We will hold our annual fireworks display at the festival grounds in Kasenjiki Park tonight, starting at 7:00.
Please invite everybody and come on out.
It's hot, isn't it, Yamazaki?
So what about it?
Your A/C doesn't seem to be working.
It's been temperamental since a little while back.
I guess it finally gave out.
Oh, really.
We will hold our annual fireworks display at the festival grounds in Kasenjiki park tonight, starting at 7:00.
Please invite everybody and come on out.
Yamazaki, want to go to the fireworks?
We don't have that kind of spare time.
But wouldn't a little mood change increase our work efficiency?
Even so, it doesn't have to be fireworks, right?!
Well, that's true, but still...
No good comes out of going to see stupid fireworks.
That's right...
No good at all.
Yamazaki...
Sato!
I finished the color design for the heroine.
I dropped it into "Shared Files," so give it a check, please.
Right.
Wow, it looks pretty good!
The heroine Rei's secret is revealed in a classroom of the hero's school.
Rei!
I have nothing. I have nothing!
You're wrong!
You have me, don't you?
I'll protect you, even if it turns the whole world against me!
Sato...
Rei...
What's with you?
Huh? It's, uh, it's nothing.
Why does everything turn into her face?
This is great, Yamazaki. Good job.
Before they journey off into a different world, the hero and Rei go to the beach to make memories.
Sato, you come out here too!
Rei!
Sorry!
It's okay.
I don't mind being seen if it's by you, Sato.
R-Rei...
It's okay, Sato.
Sato!
Oh, it's nothing. It's nothing.
I'm sick of this. How am I supposed to concentrate?
Damn, why did she appear again?
So, this is her first outfit when they go to a different world, huh?
That means this is...
Rei!
Are you all right, Rei?
Thanks, Sato.
What the hell has come over me?
Ouch...
Sato, you're worried about real-life romance, aren't you?
Huh?
Misaki, was that her name?
You've thought of nothing but her for a while now, haven't you?
Uh, no.
It's not that I'm thinking of her;
she just pops up in my head of her own accord.
That must mean you're actually in love with her!
Now that you mention it...
I can't believe I'm in love with a girl like that...
You're ridiculous, Sato.
What?
Girls are just human beings, right?
All this "love" stuff doesn't exist in the three-dimensional world!
Do you hear me?
Originally, romantic love didn't exist in Japan.
Arranged marriages and late-night trysts were all there were.
This "romantic love" stuff is a custom that came in from overseas!
Romantic love is a trap to expand the capitalist system!
And you're gonna let it dance you around like a puppet?!
We have to get on the other side of it and turn this "love" illusion into a way to make money!
You say that, but what about you?
Aren't you in love with that Nanako girl?
Nanako's even the model for this heroine, isn't she?!
We will hold our annual fireworks display at the festival grounds in Kasenjiki park tonight, starting at 7:00.
Please invite everybody and come on out.
Fireworks displays can just vanish from this world!
I was on the brink of stupidly repeating the same mistake again.
The same mistake?
It was when I was still in elementary school...
You dork!
Nyah-nyah.
Dumb-head.
You make me sick!
You're lame-o.
You're a loser.
Stop it!
Oh no, Paruko's here!
Everybody run for cover before she tells on us!
Get out of here! It's Paruko! Run!
Hey, you! Hold on!
Who are you calling Paruko?
Are you okay?
Come to think of it, that was my first crush.
But I was already set to transfer schools when the first term ended,
I asked her to the fireworks so I'd at least have a last remembrance.
I'm sorry.
But tomorrow I sort of...
...sort of have to...
...go see my sick grandfather.
That's how my first crush ended all too soon.
But if that had really been the end, I might still have been saved!
What?
Miki!
Get lost, villains.
Get lost, villains!
Women lie with a straight face!
Even that Nanako, all the while she was saying she had some audition,
but I'm positive she's on a date with another guy!
The same goes for that Misaki!
It's for damn sure she's laughing at you, Sato the hikikomori, behind your back!
Women are a disease of this world!
We have to bring down the iron hammer of Justice upon the world's women!
Get lost, women!
Come on, Sato, say it with me!
G-Get lost, women.
Too soft!
Put this on and try again!
Get lost, women.
Put more enmity into it and say it again.
Get lost, women! Get lost, women!
Get lost, women! Get lost, women! Get lost, women! Get lost, women!
Wonder who that is?
Nanako-tan
Hello? Nanako?
Shut up!
Could you keep quiet for me, please?
Hello? What's up with the sudden call?
The thing is, the audition suddenly got postponed.
So, I remembered the fireworks display you were talking about.
I'm actually at the station already.
Really?
Yes! It's no problem for me at all!
I'll come to meet you there. Wait there, please!
See you!
A change of mood is necessary, isn't it?
That being so, I'm going out.
Sato, keep working hard on that script, please.
Get lost, everybody.
You can all get shot by fireworks and die.
I still have quite a while until counseling time.
Ow!
Oh! I'm sorry!
Misaki?
Um, it's about today's counseling... I'd like to cancel.
On that note...
Won't you come with me to see the fireworks?
Might this not be a trap?
After this, I'll bet there's going to be a big backlash.
But if it's this kind of trap,
maybe it's all right.
Episode 9
Welcome to a Summer Day!
Ababa, ababa, ababa, dancing baby human!
ababa ababa ababa odoru akachan ningen hogya
When we were born naked,
hito wa hadaka de umareta toki wa
we were all loved equally, just as it's supposed to be.
dare mo aisare onajina hazu ga
But why, as life goes on,
doushite nano da ikite iku uchi
does each destiny take a different path? It's almost cruel.
sadame wa wakare mugoi kurai da
Some can look at other's eyes, while others can't.
hito no me mitari mirenakattari
Some get to learn love, while others don't.
koi wo shittari shirenakattari
If that's how it is, I'd rather be
sore nara boku wa isso naritai
a baby, a baby human till I die.
shinu made baby akachan ningen
"Oh, what an adorable baby!"
Ah, nante kawaii baby
"I just want to love you!"
aishitaku naru wa
(Just like I planned!)
omou tsubo daze
(It worked perfectly!)
umaku ittaze
The baby she's holding isn't really a baby human.
kanojo daita akago jitsu wa akachan ningen
"Ababa!" I snicker to myself, hiding in my pretended innocence.
adokenasa no ura de ababa hokusoemu no sa
It's so easy to be a baby human, so you should be one too!
kimi mo nare yo raku de iize baby human
Ababa, ababa! Dance, multiply, and take it to space!
ababa ababa odore fuyase soshite uchuu e
To Mars! To Saturn! To the galaxy! Dance! Baby human!
kasei e dosei e ginga e odoru yo akachan ningen
Dance! Baby human!
odoru yo akachan ningen
You slipped up, Sato.
The heroine's name is wrong.
She was watching me?
Next episode, "Welcome to the Dark Side!"
Next Episode
Welcome to the Dark Side!