I lift my eyes a little and look into the sky
sukoshi miageta sora
All I do is mutter every time,
dekisugita nichijou
as I turn my back
se wo mukeru tabi ni
on this perfect everyday life
tsubuyaku dake
"Where am I supposed to go?"
doko ni ikeba ii no
With you who are giving me a look like that?
sonna kao shiteru kimi to
In the shadows of a back alley,
rojiura no kage tokei no hari ga
the hands of a clock repaint the time that has been stopped.
tomatta jikan wo nurikaete
Extended hands,
sashinobeta ryoute
puzzle pieces that don't fit.
kamiawanai pazuru wo
Until the abandoned two
okizari ni shiteta
reunite with something
futari deau made
that has been lost.
nakushiteta nanika
Recover
saigo no kakera wo
the last piece,
torimodoshite
and let's start walking.
arukidasou
Erotic game?
If you don't like how it sounds, you can also call it a "gal game" or "moe game."
The gist of the game is the conquest of beautiful girls.
Even I know that much, but still...
Don't be surprised!
I'm a creator!
I don't know how to say this, but, it's like...
I'm not very sure about showing her a gal game.
What do you mean by that?
I think she'll despise me, rather than be impressed by me, if I show her a game like that.
"A game like that"?
She's gonna despise you if you show her a game like that?
Sato, have you ever played a gal game?
No, never...
That's what I thought.
That's why you can spout nonsense like that.
You know nothing!
Yamazaki?!
This one, this one...
This one too...
This one and this one!
They're all made by the same company!
I'm sure you don't know about this, but they're all big hits!
They have an office in a prime location in Roppongi and over a hundred employees!
At present, they are at the forefront of the gaming industry with an established reputation!
But it all started...
with this amateur gal game!
You've got to be kidding me!
Basically, gal games have hidden potential to turn an amateur into a big creator
without having to have a good academic background or connections!
A big creator?
That's right! That is why we must create a gal game!
We're gonna make it and go sell it.
It might not sell at all in the beginning since we're still no-names,
but...
I'm sure our game will eventually become popular by word of mouth
and one day start selling like hotcakes!
Y-You think so?
It will be impossible to keep up with demand doing only on-site sales.
If things come to that, the next step would be forming our own company!
I see!
Then, we'll officially get into the game production business
and start launching hit titles one after another!
The number of employees will grow as well as the size of the office!
The company will continue to grow!
Sweet!
Then we'll venture into anime production and merchandising and score big again!
Yes! Yes!
Then, at the same time we'll start to embark on ventures abroad!
Eventually, we'll become a global company everyone knows about!
Great!
Then, we'll leave our mark on history as the most successful creators that ever existed!
We'll no longer be just a couple of regular guys people can casually walk up to!
Exactly!
Sato...
So what do you think, Sato? Are you still making fun of gal games?
No! Gal games are the best!
Gal games are our ticket! Our one and only ticket!
Now that's the spirit! Let's make a great gal game ourselves!
Yeah!
First, you must understand what makes a good gal game in order to make an excellent gal game.
I've picked out my top ten gal games for you.
Try to play a few.
Yeah! I'm gonna play them all!
All right, it's finished installing.
First I have to enter my name, eh?
My name is Tatsuhiro Sato.
Nickname is Tatchan!
Big brother?
Big brother!
I said, wake up, big brother!
It's morning already!
I'm her big brother?
She's pretty cute...
Stay asleep
Jump out of bed
I shouldn't make a cute girl like her wait!
So the answer is B, of course!
Why did you get up like that all of a sudden, big brother?
Fantastic!
Hello?
Oh, Sato... What's up?
Yamazaki, those games you let me borrow...
Did you slip in some G-rated games too?
No, I didn't.
Remember, I let you borrow them as materials for game production.
They're all authentic gal games.
Then why I didn't see any scenes that contained that "certain action"?!
What?
I've spent hours and finally reached the ending!
All I saw was a couple of panty shots and changing scenes!
What's up with that?!
Please calm down, Sato.
Let me guess. You picked the answers you thought all the girls would like?
Well, that's because they're all so cute and...
Normally, you're not supposed to be able to make it with multiple girls at the same time in the gal game.
"He who grasps for everything, attains nothing." Get it?
Is that how it is?
First, pick your favorite girl.
If you keep the game focusing on her, you should be able to see good scenes.
Misao, huh?
All right, I've picked my favorite!
I'm gonna tear your clothes off first!
Hello?
Tell me what the hell is going on with this, Yamazaki!
I can't make it with Misao!
Just like you said, I gave everyone except Misao the cold shoulder the whole time!
But then, my most important character, Misao, stopped showing up!
Huh? I can't be too cold to them either?
Then what am I supposed to do?
Hm, I see. Oh, I get it...
Thanks, Yamazaki! I'll give it a try!
Jeez...
Hello?
I did it, Yamazaki! I finally saw the scene!
Good for you.
By the way,
what can I do to save this particular picture?
Good...
I'm starting to get the hang of it.
Hey, Misao, good morning!
You look pretty as usual today, Urara!
Aya!
Emiri!
Shizuka!
Sakurako!
Ruri!
Oh, everyone's great!
I get it, this must be the world of gal games!
Sato! I know you're in there!
I'm coming in.
Hey, Yamazaki! Long time no see!
These gal games are fun!
No wonder you're crazy about them.
So, I'd really appreciate it if you'd let me borrow them a little longer.
Hell, I have all the time in the world.
If you give me a month, I should be able to clear ten or twenty gal games!
A month? Don't tell me you've forgotten about the promise.
Huh? Promise?
You promised her that you're going to show her the game we made!
Oh, I forgot about that...
In creating a game,
you generally nail down the game-playing system and the world overview of the game first.
However, when you make a gal game,
the element that takes first priority is the characters!
It's not excessive to say that it's the charming and unique array of beautiful girls that one presents
that determines whether the game is a hit, or if it crashes and burns.
Really...
Now that I think about it, every one of them was charming.
Especially, Misao...
You have to come up with them, Sato!
Huh? Why me?
Because you're in charge of the scenario!
The person who writes the scenario is supposed to come up with them!
Then what are you going to do?
Programming, music production, CG and all the other miscellaneous tasks!
Basically, I'll take care of everything except the scenario.
Good luck, dude...
The girls I know are...
And...
Good grief...
As if you were a dumb high school girl!
But I am a dumb high school girl.
Sure, I know you're trying to get into Waseda University.
Say, Sato...
What is it?
Do you think you'd be sad if I died?
Sato! Can I talk to you for a sec?
Yeah, it's open.
I was hoping you could use these to create characters.
They're my secret collections that I've gathered on the Internet.
Just go over them really quickly.
See ya.
Secret collection?
A collection of pictures, huh?
I guess she looks all right.
Whoa, whoa! Is this for real?
A cute girl like her?!
Could the next one be...
*This scene is imaginary.
Is this all right?!
Don't tell me this girl too...
*This scene is imaginary.
Th-This ain't right...
Is it possible that everything on this CD is...
What the...
Who would've thought I'd be able to see photographic images with that level of awesomeness in Japan?
This is the world, eh?
Now that I think about it, Yamazaki was saying that he found these on the Internet.
If he can do it, so can I!
I'm coming to get ya, digital world!
Keyword search, commence!
Right there!
I'm not gonna let you get away!
A big one! I gotta catch it!
I'm gonna get you with this!
Oh no!
Check out my light-speed mouse maneuver!
I'm gonna collect them... I'm gonna collect them all!
The Life of an Amorous Man!
Hello?
Uh, Yamazaki?
I've got a little problem.
Can I ask you for some advice?
Huh?
I was deleting all the files I don't need, then all of a sudden it froze up.
You deleted the system file!
You do need that, you know!
Well, I've never seen that file name extension, so I figured...
First of all, the games I've lent you were pretty much the only things on your system,
so your hard drive had a lot of room.
I don't understand why you had to delete files.
Well, actually it got full as I was collecting materials...
"Materials," huh?
It should be fine now.
Really?
Thank god... You're a lifesaver, Yamazaki.
By the way, what kind of material did you collect?
H-Hey!
Don't look! Hey!
Eguchi
Moroboshi
Loli
Eguchi? Moroboshi? Lo...
My friends' personal information is in there, so you can't look!
You don't have friends!
I wasn't getting much inspiration from the materials you had given me, so...
So, you stayed locked up in here for a week straight and collected these types of images.
I guess you could say that.
You didn't take a bath or eat.
Sato, are you stupid or what?
All right, it can't be helped that you're a hikikomori,
but even I wouldn't lock myself up in here for a week and collect 120GB worth of girls' photos!
Quite honestly, I don't think it's normal!
Yeah, but Nozomi is so pretty and...
Kiyomi is unbelievably wild and...
Rika is the cutest and...
Sato, get a hold of yourself!
Do you realize what people would think of you if they saw you like this?
Right now you're just an ugly, pitiful and filthy-looking pervert!
Not to mention, you're the worst hikikomori loser!
My childhood dream was to become a scholar and do something to help others.
So, how the hell did this happen to me?!
You must face reality, Sato!
Face reality?
Good grief, how did he even...
He should focus his passion on something else!
This isn't bad at all...
S-Sato?
I have to face reality!
Yamazaki, you bring your own camera too!
What?
Sato!
I thought you were a hikikomori!
It's not time to be a hikikomori right now!
Yamazaki, what did you call me earlier?
Um, an ugly, pitiful and filthy-looking pervert.
Exactly!
I'm about to do something only a pervert would do!
Huh?
Yamazaki, take pictures of me!
Take pictures of me and show them to me!
Why would you want me to do such a thing?
I don't understand what you're trying to do at all.
A man won't be able to change unless he faces reality!
Looking at pictures of myself, taken by you, will make me see myself as others see me
and I'll probably fall into a state of self-hatred.
But I'm sure that self-hatred could be turned into an energy that could change who I am right now!
I am... I am...
I am going to...
Break free of this darkness!
Class is now over.
Soon girls will be coming through the gate.
I will take pictures of them.
The so-called "sneak pictures."
What do you think?
Isn't that just what an ugly, pitiful and filthy-looking pervert would do?
Sato-san!
I'm ugly, right? I'm pitiful, right?
But that is exactly who I am right now!
How did this happen?
I wanted to have a normal, healthy life.
Here they come, Yamazaki!
Listen, be sure to take pictures of me doing this, all right?
What are you doing, Sato?
Like I said, I'm taking sneak photos of girls!
Girls?
Why?
Yamazaki? Yamazaki?
You mean the guy who was standing here?
He covered his face and ran away.
What?
Um, Sato...
Are you, by any chance,
into young girls?
No, I'm not!
I had no choice! I had to do it to collect materials!
Remember I told you that I'm a creator, so...
Oh yeah...
Now that I think about it, taking all the girls' photos is part of the material gathering process.
That's the truth!
What's that?
What a moron!
That's nasty!
I gotta go home, right now!
Sato!
I could help you, you know?
Sato...
Just like I thought, you're that kind of person.
N-No! That was just a spinal reflex, and...
No, I mean,
This is for gathering materials! I have no choice!
But I guess it's better that way...
Huh?
Yeah, in fact, it's perfect for my project if you're that way.
What? What?
Let's meet again.
Don't do anything that would get you in the news, okay?
What the hell is up with her?
Episode 03
Welcome to the Beautiful Girls!
I don't get it!
Ababa, ababa, ababa, dancing baby human!
ababa ababa ababa odoru akachan ningen hogya
When we were born naked,
hito wa hadaka de umareta toki wa
we were all loved equally, just as it's supposed to be.
dare mo aisare onajina hazu ga
But why, as life goes on,
doushite nano da ikite iku uchi
does each destiny take a different path? It's almost cruel.
sadame wa wakare mugoi kurai da
Some can look at other's eyes, while others can't.
hito no me mitari mirenakattari
Some get to learn love, while others don't.
koi wo shittari shirenakattari
If that's how it is, I'd rather be
sore nara boku wa isso naritai
a baby, a baby human till I die.
shinu made baby akachan ningen
"Oh, what an adorable baby!"
Ah, nante kawaii baby
"I just want to love you!"
aishitaku naru wa
(Just like I planned!)
omou tsubo daze
(It worked perfectly!)
umaku ittaze
The baby she's holding isn't really a baby human.
kanojo daita akago jitsu wa akachan ningen
"Ababa!" I snicker to myself, hiding in my pretended innocence.
adokenasa no ura de ababa hokusoemu no sa
It's so easy to be a baby human, so you should be one too!
kimi mo nare yo raku de iize baby human
Ababa, ababa! Dance, multiply, and take it to space!
ababa ababa odore fuyase soshite uchuu e
To Mars! To Saturn! To the galaxy! Dance! Baby human!
kasei e dosei e ginga e odoru yo akachan ningen
Dance! Baby human!
odoru yo akachan ningen
What's up with this town?
Long time no see, Sato.
This is the sub-culture that Japan prides itself on!
Next episode, "Welcome to the New World!"
Next Episode
Welcome to the New World!