I lift my eyes a little and look into the sky
sukoshi miageta sora
All I do is mutter every time,
dekisugita nichijou
as I turn my back
se wo mukeru tabi ni
on this perfect everyday life
tsubuyaku dake
"Where am I supposed to go?"
doko ni ikeba ii no
With you who are giving me a look like that?
sonna kao shiteru kimi to
In the shadows of a back alley,
rojiura no kage tokei no hari ga
the hands of a clock repaint the time that has been stopped.
tomatta jikan wo nurikaete
Extended hands,
sashinobeta ryoute
puzzle pieces that don't fit.
kamiawanai pazuru wo
Until the abandoned two
okizari ni shiteta
reunite with something
futari deau made
that has been lost.
nakushiteta nanika
Recover
saigo no kakera wo
the last piece,
torimodoshite
and let's start walking.
arukidasou
This sun is awfully hot for 9:00 in the morning.
But even so, this is just the thing to refresh my rotted brain.
I'm going to be reborn, starting today.
It's a revolution!
One to keep this girl smiling.
It's beginning,
my journey with her.
It's a new departure for just the two of us.
What the... What's up with that gloomy group?
That's ominous, for a new departure on a clear day.
Sorry to keep you waiting. Shall we go?
Sure!
Uh, hold on, Senpai!
I'm Hana-Hana.
So, she knows these people?
Uh, this is a guy I knew from high school,
And what's this "Hana-Hana" stuff? And she was meeting them here?
And we're not taking a vacation just the two of us?
And when I told him about today's offline meeting,
he said he wanted to take part.
And...
Right, Sato?
Yes?
Yes!
So, this is that guy, the one you talked about on the forum.
Yes, it's him.
I guess it's all right. Well, shall we get going?
Sato?
Huh? Right!
Akira Jogasaki
Sorry to keep you waiting.
Oh, wow!
This boat belongs to you, Mr. Minegishi?
It's the first time I've been on one of these, Senpai!
So, you really did own a cabin cruiser.
Would you rather I'd been lying?
If it were a lie, the offline meeting itself would have been called off.
In that case...
What are you talking about? We've come all this way!
We can't call it off now!
You're absolutely right.
Let's hurry up and go to this island of yours.
Uh, Senpai...
What is it?
There are parts of our talk last night that I don't remember exactly.
Where was it we're going again?
An uninhabited island.
What?
It's an island privately owned by "Mr. God", I guess his real name is Mr. Minegishi.
He says it has a very lovely sandy beach
and it's just like Paradise.
An appropriate place for us now, isn't it?
I don't need it anymore.
But...
Senpai...
Hitomi
Mr. Jogasaki, we're ready.
I see.
All right, hit it for me.
Yeah, bingo.
This means we should be able to wrap this up today, huh?
It's a bit early, but let's all grab lunch together.
We'll take care of the rest ourselves.
What's left is all simple work,
so there's no need for you to use up your time looking over it, Mr. Jogasaki.
You have plans with your girlfriend, right?
Ah, Hitomi?!
The cellular phone you are calling is either in a locale without cellular service or is turned off.
Uh, we placed a reservation recently.
Yes...
No, if it's been cancelled, that's fine.
Sorry for the trouble.
An Introduction to the Study of Poisons
There's a dock here and everything, huh?
Apparently, a wealthy capitalist once had a summer home here.
I bought it from his relatives who put it up for an Internet auction.
Wow...
It really is amazing!
I've never seen a real private beach before!
It's a revolution!
Hey!
Ah, it feels good.
The only ones here are Senpai and those other three.
I don't have to be afraid of strangers looking at me.
It truly is Paradise.
You mustn't! Absolutely not!
I, too, tentatively declare I'll participate.
I plan to drink at a high-school friend's place tonight.
I decided a little while ago.
I haven't contacted him yet, but since he's a hikikomori, it's for certain he's home.
I've known him a long time, so I have to say goodbye to him beforehand anyway.
Address: 202 Mita House, Kawasaki City, Kanagawa Prefecture
I apologize if I drink too much and I'm late. You can leave without me.
Oh! Hot-hot-hot-hot!
Huh? You're not going to swim?
Sorry, seems like last night's alcohol is still with me.
What's the story with these guys?
Coming all this way to the beach and not even swimming...
Isn't an offline meeting a place to be more rowdy and have fun?
This is nothing but a gathering of hikikomoris.
Although, that includes me too.
No! This summer I'll be reborn.
Yes! It's a revolution!
First thing is to make friendly talk with the people I just met today.
That's a high-level technique a hikikomori couldn't possibly pull off.
Uh, hi!
He ignored me?!
No, no, the new Sato isn't going to be discouraged by something like being ignored once.
What game are you playing? I play a lot too.
I play gal-games though.
I have a younger friend who knows all about games; he's a real game otaku... Huh?
Hey...
Did I say something inappropriate?
No, no, the new Sato doesn't get discouraged by this kind of stuff.
I've had a revolution after all.
Here goes, I'll get it this time.
Hey there.
No, no, I assumed I'd get that sort of reaction.
Relax, New Sato.
Senpai told me before that you're a medical student.
I'm a former medical student.
I don't attend school anymore.
Oops, that may have been a touchy subject.
Since I said that, I'll expose something shameful about myself.
Yeah, the fact is, I'm a hikikomori.
Huh?
I don't suppose there's some medicine that could make me feel super-energetic?
If you have some, I'd love for you to share it with me.
Are you stupid or what?
If I gave you that potent a medicine without a prescription,
it'd be a violation of the pharmaceutical laws.
Either way, there's no medicine to cure a hikikomori.
He really doesn't have to talk as bluntly as that when somebody's just trying to be friendly.
Is there still something you want to say?
Well, I don't necessarily have to talk to him.
I have other people to talk to.
Yeah! That older guy will talk.
Relax, Sato, it's a revolution.
Will you drink one?
You're amazing, Mr. Minegishi, with that boat and this island.
Am I?
How can a person acquire stuff like this?
As someone with life experience, please tell me!
What's the point of asking that?
The... The point...
It's true I've acquired things ordinary people couldn't acquire.
But in exchange, I lost so much.
Like an ordinary person's happiness.
Do you still want to ask?
Uh, no.
It's not that I wanted that desperately to ask.
Ex-Excuse me!
Why?
With this many human beings around...
why am I so lonely?
Even though I came all the way out to this island paradise...
...even though it's our last Culture Festival!
Wait, I wonder if that's also how the class rep felt back then?
Please be quiet! Homeroom isn't finished yet!
This is our last Culture Festival, you know!
I remember that was the time we were deciding what to put out for the Culture Festival.
So, let's all make it an amazing one that"ll be a great memory!
My noisy classmates were ignoring the class rep, who was struggling all by herself, and I was among them.
What are you so worked up about?
Is that the assertiveness of youth?
You're a joke.
At the time, I thought it was cooler to be detached.
I was detached toward studying, toward romance, toward friendship...
And the conclusion of all that was life as a hikikomori, huh?
Sato! Get up, please!
It's already past noon!
Sato, hurry up!
The first day of the Comic Stall is gonna be over!
Sato!
Damn it! I can't believe I overslept on this crucial day!
You... You're that girl Sato knows.
Uh, well...
What is it?
Did Sato come back?
What? Did Sato go out?
Stop joking around, please. He's a hikikomori.
There's no way he could go all alone to a place with so many people like the Comic Stall, right?
He wasn't alone.
He went with a woman in a car.
That was somebody else you saw.
There's no way he has anyone like that.
But...
No, hold on.
There is one person.
If it were Hitomi Kashiwa from the Literature Club,
he might go off somewhere with her.
Is what you just said true?
Would you be willing to tell me a few more specifics?
What are you doing?!
I thought I'd collect some driftwood and have a campfire.
What?! Are you an idiot?
There's no point!
Nobody's interested in that kind of thing!
Hey!
Oh, thanks.
Give me a break... Well, what can you do?
Thanks to you, I remembered the original purpose of this offline meeting.
Right...
The purpose?
Yes.
The reason we all gathered together in a place like this
was that we thought we'd spend at least the last day of our lives pleasantly.
Ah, I see.
Eh?!
"The last day of our lives"?!
This... This is...
Hitomi may be taking part in this offline meeting with Sato!
Offline meeting?
The Island Nearest to Paradise?
Let's end our lives,
Huh?
They intend to end their lives today!
Se-Senpai...
Episode 12
Welcome to the Offline Meeting!
Nobody told me about this!
Ababa, ababa, ababa, dancing baby human!
ababa ababa ababa odoru akachan ningen hogya
When we were born naked,
hito wa hadaka de umareta toki wa
we were all loved equally, just as it's supposed to be.
dare mo aisare onajina hazu ga
But why, as life goes on,
doushite nano da ikite iku uchi
does each destiny take a different path? It's almost cruel.
sadame wa wakare mugoi kurai da
Some can look at other's eyes, while others can't.
hito no me mitari mirenakattari
Some get to learn love, while others don't.
koi wo shittari shirenakattari
If that's how it is, I'd rather be
sore nara boku wa isso naritai
a baby, a baby human till I die.
shinu made baby akachan ningen
"Oh, what an adorable baby!"
Ah, nante kawaii baby
"I just want to love you!"
aishitaku naru wa
(Just like I planned!)
omou tsubo daze
(It worked perfectly!)
umaku ittaze
The baby she's holding isn't really a baby human.
kanojo daita akago jitsu wa akachan ningen
"Ababa!" I snicker to myself, hiding in my pretended innocence.
adokenasa no ura de ababa hokusoemu no sa
It's so easy to be a baby human, so you should be one too!
kimi mo nare yo raku de iize baby human
Ababa, ababa! Dance, multiply, and take it to space!
ababa ababa odore fuyase soshite uchuu e
To Mars! To Saturn! To the galaxy! Dance! Baby human!
kasei e dosei e ginga e odoru yo akachan ningen
Dance! Baby human!
odoru yo akachan ningen
You're a hikikomori, more pathetic than a stray dog!
It's already too late to turn back.
This is a conspiracy.
Next episode, "Welcome to Paradise!"
Next Episode
Welcome to Paradise!