I lift my eyes a little and look into the sky
sukoshi miageta sora
All I do is mutter every time,
dekisugita nichijou
as I turn my back
se wo mukeru tabi ni
on this perfect everyday life
tsubuyaku dake
"Where am I supposed to go?"
doko ni ikeba ii no
With you who are giving me a look like that?
sonna kao shiteru kimi to
In the shadows of a back alley,
rojiura no kage tokei no hari ga
the hands of a clock repaint the time that has been stopped.
tomatta jikan wo nurikaete
Extended hands,
sashinobeta ryoute
puzzle pieces that don't fit.
kamiawanai pazuru wo
Until the abandoned two
okizari ni shiteta
reunite with something
futari deau made
that has been lost.
nakushiteta nanika
Recover
saigo no kakera wo
the last piece,
torimodoshite
and let's start walking.
arukidasou
But I'm sure you'll be fine.
Because I know how to get out of it.
Huh?
Besides I've known about you for a long time.
I have come to rescue you.
Welcome to the project!
Project
To Tatsuhiro Sato,
You have been chosen for my project.
Therefore please come to Mita Park on 4th Street at 9:00 tonight,
Misaki Nakahara.
Here.
This is the contract.
A contract regarding how to escape the hikikomori state and recovery support...
But it's handwritten.
And on top of that, the penalty charge is one hundred thousand yen?!
I want to help you, Sato.
A-Are you really okay with hanging out with a weirdo like me this late at night?
Beware of Molesters
Call 119 if you spot suspicious activities.
It's dangerous.
So Sato, were you the guilty party?
Hell no!
Then it's okay, right?
Besides my house is right around the corner.
Is this a part of soliciting too?
Huh?
You know, about yesterday...
Oh, not at all.
I was just tagging along with my Aunt Kazuko.
I've caused all kinds of problems for my aunt for a long time,
so that was the least I could do for her.
More importantly, go ahead and sign the contract.
You wanna know how to escape being a hikikomori, don't you?
I'll tell you how, once you sign the contract, Sato!
Don't talk to me like I'm your friend! You're younger than me! Show some respect!
Do you know how old I am?
I... I... I'd guess around 17 or 18.
Yup, you're correct.
I'm not a hikikomori!
Wait up, Sato!
I'm telling you, you're going to regret this!
This could be your last chance, you know?
I'll be waiting for you at the same time tomorrow, okay?
Sign this and bring it back. All right, Sato?
I don't get this...
Contract Re: How to Escape the Hikikomori State and Recovery Support
Hikikomori Subject: Tatsuhiro Sato
Recovery Supporter: Misaki Nakahara
Misaki Nakahara...
Shut up!
Hello, everyone!
We'll bring you today's show with our lovely guests!
Afternoon Time! I'm your host Sewashi Sekiya.
And today's guests are...
Another day is coming to an end,
a day void of any significant events.
How long am I going to repeat days like this?
A long time ago, I read a sci-fi novel like this...
The story takes place in the near future, after the human race is annihilated in the final war.
The main character is the only survivor.
Certain life forms from outer space, to put it simply, aliens,
decide to keep this main character alive as a test sample.
So they create a simulation of Earth as it had been,
and try to hide the truth that mankind had been wiped out from him.
However, if he were to spend too much time outside of his house,
he would figure out that the world he lives in is a fake.
So they decide to make the main character a NEET so they can isolate him.
The main character, me, Tatsuhiro Sato,
kept alive as part of a horrifying alien conspiracy...
Dreams and hopes
Magical girl, that's...
This contract is made by and between the person who suffers from hikikomorism, hereinafter "subject"
and the person who helps him/her recover from the condition, hereinafter "supporter".
Both parties agree to the terms as follows:
1) The Subject must disclose all feelings, including but not limited to:
Distress, conflict, complaints, negative thoughts, etc.
Regarding hikikomori recovery procedures to the Supporter.
Signing this damned paper would fix my hikikomori condition? Yeah, right.
I'll be waiting for you at the same time tomorrow, okay?
That chick is totally clueless!
What kind of hikikomori would go outside two days in a row anyway?
We're called "hikikomori" because we don't go outside!
I'm not a hikikomori!
I'm a...
liar!
This could be your last chance, you know?
Maybe it really was my last chance.
But now the chance is gone.
Could she be still waiting for me out there?
Beware of Molesters
Call 119 if you spot suspicious activities.
Damn! That park is...
Hello, little girl!
Noooo!
Oh, no, no way!
Misaki Nakahara Emergency Press Conference
I was supposed to meet my friend there,
but he didn't show up.
I kept on waiting and waiting, and then...
What's your friend's name?
What kind of relationship do you have with him?
Mr. Sato, can we talk to you for a minute?
We know you're in there! Please come out!
Because of your hikikomori condition, an innocent young girl has been deeply scarred!
Aren't you going to apologize to her?
Is it my fault?
Beware of Molesters
Call 119 if you spot suspicious activities.
There she is...
Jeez, you're an hour late!
You... What the hell are you?!
I'm a sweet little girl,
who's willing to rescue a hikikomori loser!
But I'm not a hikikomori!
Liar!
It was quite obvious when my aunt and I met you.
But I told you guys that I'm not!
But normally people wouldn't get flustered like that unless they are hikikomori.
Did you bring the contract?
I am not a hikikomori!
I know.
You come to this park every Sunday night and do nothing but gaze into space, right?
But other than that, you don't go outside at all.
No matter how you look at it, that's a hikikomori condition.
Well, it's... it's true that I'm always in my apartment,
but I can't help it because of my work!
What is your work?
That's...
SOHO...
SOHO?
It means "small office home office"!
In other words, I'm working from home, so it's not like I'm unemployed!
But you came to the coffee shop for a job interview.
Oh, I just did that on a whim! That was an impulse!
Then let me ask you this.
What kind of job do you have?
Don't be surprised.
I said, don't be surprised!
I...
I'm a creator!
Since my job requires me to be creative, I may come off sort of weird,
but that's just an aspect of my brilliant talent!
So, what do you create?
Well, it's...
the most advanced, revolutionary IT...
Oh yeah! It's computer-related!
Software development, that is!
Right now, I'm in the middle of making software! It's so awesome it'd put even Bill or Linus to shame!
Be sure to bring the contract tomorrow, okay?
Hey...
What was that reaction?
"Bring it tomorrow," my ass!
How dare she look at me like she's some kind of know-it-all?!
I've got a computer!
I could easily write a program or two...
Oh, who am I kidding?
Shut the hell up!
Today is the day!
I'm not going to put up with this anymore!
Hey, come out now!
If you don't come out, I'll break it down myself!
Son of a bitch!
Turn that shit down! Turn off that goddamn animu song!
Sato?
Huh?
You're Sato, right?
Is this for real? Are you real?
You...
So you're the anime otaku who moved in next door,
Yamazaki?
Literature Club
Hey, you.
Join the Literature Club.
Those few words made me decide to spend my three high school years in the Literature Club.
Of course, I had no interest in novels whatsoever.
So, my daily club activities were playing cards and hanging out with her,
listening to her bizarre conspiracy theories.
Jeez, what the hell was I doing back then?
I'm sure there were lots of other things I could have been doing.
Two years rolled by very fast.
And one day, shortly before her graduation...
Look...
Yeah, that's bullying, right?
That's terrible.
Should I go help the guy?
Could you?
Come on, they're just middle school kids.
Bullying is not cool!
Quickly the hunter became the hunted.
She was amazed how pathetic I was,
but supposedly the guy being bullied was deeply moved by my actions.
Literature Club
Senpai!
I'd like to join the club!
That was Yamazaki.
Four years after my graduation, this is an unexpected reunion indeed.
Sorry, it's messy. Please have a seat.
Yeah...
Who would've thought the anime song freak next door was Yamazaki?
Sorry about the noise.
I guess the walls of this apartment are pretty thin, huh?
Besides, I've been listening to it every single day,
Usually, people would realize stuff like that a few days after they moved in.
I guess I've become numb to the sound.
At any rate, I'm surprised.
I didn't realize you live right next door to me,
but I always knew that you'd go to college in Tokyo though.
This is your fourth year, right?
Y-Yeah...
I've been going to a vocational school in Tokyo since this spring.
I was looking for an apartment that's easy to commute from and cheap.
Then I found this place and I liked it.
Actually, I was already predicting that he'd probably end up like this four years ago.
So, have you been bullied at the school you go to now?
You were crying earlier, weren't you?
People in my class are nothing but morons!
They don't know a thing about video games!
But they all act like they know what they're talking about!
Girls are the worst!
I just wanna ask them why they even bother coming to the school at all.
At this rate, there's no hope for the future of Japan's video game industry!
Up we go...
Sato?
Let's drink.
Yeah!
Oh yeah, I remember that.
Seriously, it was so much fun back then.
I wish those carefree days had never ended.
No kidding.
Game Creator Department
Kokogi Designer Institute
Designer Institute?
Yeah, haven't you seen the TV commercial before?
Actually, I've been going to the Game Creator Department of the school.
Game Creator Department
Kokogi Designer Institute
Game Creator Department...
Don't be surprised!
I'm a creator!
Yamazaki, can I borrow this?
Beware of Molesters
Call 119 if you spot suspicious activities.
You're right on time today.
Did you bring the contract?
What I told you last night wasn't a lie.
I graduated from the Game Creator Department of a design institute!
This book looks like it's brand new.
I only have to read things once to get the general idea.
I've been that way all my life.
What does "object-oriented" mean?
Anyway, now you understand that I'm a creator, right?
Then will you show it to me?
Huh?
The game you've made.
Beware of Molesters
Call 119 if you spot suspicious activities.
W-Well, it's not finished yet, and I'm not supposed to show it to the general public.
Your graduation project would do too.
That's just junk that I made before I became a pro.
So anything but that...
You are very gifted, right?
If... If you insist, fine, I'll show it to you!
My masterpiece from the past!
But not right away though.
I don't even remember where I put it,
And besides, I'm busy with some of my most important work right now.
It'd probably be sometime next month.
Okay, next month then.
I'll contact you again.
All right...
Sato!
Y-Yamazaki?!
You're a college-dropout and have been a hikikomori for the last three years.
Who would've thought that you're a NEET?!
Not only that, you told such a huge lie just to impress a girl!
It kinda slipped out on the spur of the moment...
Oh, by the way, Yamazaki, I have a little favor to ask of you...
If you're thinking about asking me to lend you a game I've made, forget about it!
I just started classes at that school myself!
I don't have anything that's decent enough to let you borrow!
Wanna try to make one?
What?
A game.
And not just to show off for some girl.
If you succeed, you might be able to recover from being a NEET!
And gaining experience is beneficial for me.
Do you want to make a game together?
Let's do it, Yamazaki!
Sato, what kind of skills do you have?
Skills?
For example, can you draw, or make music or program?
Oh, I'm totally hopeless when it comes to stuff like that.
So, that means scripting the scenario is about the only think you could do.
Scenario?
It's the scriptwriting.
Oh, hell no, I haven't "composed" anything since I was in middle school.
But you were in the Literature Club, weren't you?!
Think about this. Have you ever read any novel written by me?
Now that I think about it, never.
First of all writing stuff is a pain in the ass.
Do you wanna do this or not?! Well?!
Oh, I remember...
Even though he's a wuss, he can be short-tempered and very argumentative.
That's why he was bullied to begin with.
I'll do it! I'll do it!
I should be able to come up with something for the scenario!
Good, then...
Now the problem is time, since you promised her that you were going to show it to her next month.
Even if we had a little bit more time...
Is making a game such a big deal?
Of course!
When it comes to a big project, it usually takes a few of years to produce it,
a several hundred people to work on it and hundreds of billion yen to fund it.
What?!
However, there are people out there with no money or help.
They can't even program anything decent, and all they have is some crappy music.
However, even if one's situation is that miserable,
there's a certain game genre that still allows you to produce a game,
and if you're lucky, get rich quick!
That's awesome, Yamazaki! That is it then!
But this road will be difficult and painted in our sweat and blood.
You can't tell me, "You know what? I quit!" In the middle of production!
I won't! I promise!
So, what is the game genre you're talking about?
Erotic game.
What?
Episode 02
Welcome to the Creator!
Somebody help me!
Ababa, ababa, ababa, dancing baby human!
ababa ababa ababa odoru akachan ningen hogya
When we were born naked,
hito wa hadaka de umareta toki wa
we were all loved equally, just as it's supposed to be.
dare mo aisare onajina hazu ga
But why, as life goes on,
doushite nano da ikite iku uchi
does each destiny take a different path? It's almost cruel.
sadame wa wakare mugoi kurai da
Some can look at other's eyes, while others can't.
hito no me mitari mirenakattari
Some get to learn love, while others don't.
koi wo shittari shirenakattari
If that's how it is, I'd rather be
sore nara boku wa isso naritai
a baby, a baby human till I die.
shinu made baby akachan ningen
"Oh, what an adorable baby!"
Ah, nante kawaii baby
"I just want to love you!"
aishitaku naru wa
(Just like I planned!)
omou tsubo daze
(It worked perfectly!)
umaku ittaze
The baby she's holding isn't really a baby human.
kanojo daita akago jitsu wa akachan ningen
"Ababa!" I snicker to myself, hiding in my pretended innocence.
adokenasa no ura de ababa hokusoemu no sa
It's so easy to be a baby human, so you should be one too!
kimi mo nare yo raku de iize baby human
Ababa, ababa! Dance, multiply, and take it to space!
ababa ababa odore fuyase soshite uchuu e
To Mars! To Saturn! To the galaxy! Dance! Baby human!
kasei e dosei e ginga e odoru yo akachan ningen
Dance! Baby human!
odoru yo akachan ningen
The ocean of the Internet is my ocean!
Quite honestly, I don't think it's normal!
So this is the world, eh?
Next Episode
Welcome to the Beautiful Girls!
Next episode, "Welcome to the Beautiful Girls!"