I lift my eyes a little and look into the sky
sukoshi miageta sora
All I do is mutter every time,
dekisugita nichijou
as I turn my back
se wo mukeru tabi ni
on this perfect everyday life
tsubuyaku dake
"Where am I supposed to go?"
doko ni ikeba ii no
With you who are giving me a look like that?
sonna kao shiteru kimi to
In the shadows of a back alley,
rojiura no kage tokei no hari ga
the hands of a clock repaint the time that has been stopped.
tomatta jikan wo nurikaete
Extended hands,
sashinobeta ryoute
puzzle pieces that don't fit.
kamiawanai pazuru wo
Until the abandoned two
okizari ni shiteta
reunite with something
futari deau made
that has been lost.
nakushiteta nanika
Recover
saigo no kakera wo
the last piece,
torimodoshite
and let's start walking.
arukidasou
Big brother?!
Those jerks wouldn't have...
Toro Toro?
You're Toro Toro, aren't you? I'm Mia!
Toro Toro...
That's the character who helped when we slayed that dragon.
So, it was this guy, huh?
Huh? What?
What are you doing, you people?!
Megumi! I've told you not to bring anyone to the house, right?!
I'm sorry, big brother.
Get out of this room! Immediately!
O-Okay...
Megumi! Don't bring shame upon your big brother like this!
I'm sorry!
Stop it!
I'll make your meal and bring it right away, okay?!
You guys haven't gone home yet?
Here.
That's good, Sato.
This means you'll avoid falling into debt.
My repayment of my debts just got further away though.
Um...
What about that stuff that cures the hikikomori state by eating it?
If hikikomorism could be cured by something like that, I wouldn't be suffering.
You saw the state my big brother's in, right?
So, he's a hikikomori, I guess.
"If you join Mouseroad,
you can get supplements that will cure your brother's reclusion,
and you can also attain a large income."
I was drawn in with words like that too, in the beginning.
But the reality is just as you see.
No matter how many supplements I fed him,
my brother's hikikomori condition didn't improve.
I wasn't able to meet my quotas, and my debt load kept increasing!
I realize I'm stuck in a hole, but...
"Maybe everything will start to spin into some kind of a good rhythm!"
With thinking like that, you can't grab any opportunity to quit.
I truly wonder how long I'm supposed to keep up this kind of life?
Big brother, your lunch is ready.
My brother came to Tokyo two years before me.
I got accepted to a university in Tokyo too, and we ended up living together,
but even by that time he had already been a hikikomori for more than a year.
Not going to college, and not working either,
he was just entirely absorbed in his online games.
I heard that impatience was a no-no in dealing with a hikikomori,
so my intention was to treat him with patience.
I even tried online games, to try to understand a little better how he felt,
but very soon I had no free time to be playing games.
Huh?
I told you before, right?
My father keeled over.
Our living allowance got cut off,
and the only way to get money for school and living expenses was to earn it ourselves.
There was no way my brother could work,
so all I could do was strive on my own.
I didn't have the leisure of thinking about respectability or anything.
I chose the jobs where I could earn the maximum possible income.
But when it rains, it pours, right?
Every place I worked went out of business,
and I had never once gotten paid properly for my work.
It was at that time that someone from Mouseroad approached me.
After that, it went just as you see.
That's the end of my story.
Are you satisfied, Sato,
as to why the deadly-earnest egomaniac Class Rep ended up like this?
If you understand, then go home,
because I need to go look for a sucker to take your place.
Are you going to keep at this?
I told you already, I can't turn back anymore.
Sato...
Big brother...
Let's go home, Sato. Our business is finished now.
I guess you're right.
Easy to Understand Jung
Sociophobic Hikikomori: What the Family Can Do
Sato, wait a minute.
Huh?
My brother says he wants to talk to you.
To me?
Please!
All right...
Not directly...
What?
Online?
Are you sure you want to login with the above settings?
Cancel
I've been waiting for you, Sa-To.
Toro Toro...
Is that my brother?
You didn't know that?
I knew he was playing this game,
but I didn't know what kind of character he was using.
I wonder what in the world he wants to talk about?
How's the R.M.T.? Is it going well?
I gave up games already.
I'm not going to do R.M.T. either.
You've got surprisingly little guts. You had just started, right?
I'll bet you never even succeeded in making one trade.
The entire world of games is a big pack of lies, right?
The stories of people making a lot of money at R.M.T. are just like urban legends, right?
It's absolutely impossible for beginners!
You realize that too, right?
But maybe someday, somebody will make a success of it.
That might be you.
It might be me.
Huh?
A wonderful future of vast wealth might be right in front of you.
Let it go already! What vast wealth? What wonderful future?
Look at the reality! Are you an idiot?
Class Rep...
Your little sister...
She's even turned to some shady pyramid scheme to earn money for both of your living expenses!
Her future is a black hole!
Isn't what you're doing simple escapism?
You're spending all your time dreaming comfortable dreams,
and not facing up to reality, right?!
I didn't think you'd say such harsh things to me.
What?
I mean, I was thinking we're both alike in not facing reality.
The truth is, I already understand what I should do now, and what it would take to make my life go well.
I've read 200 self-help books.
I've even thought of writing one myself.
I understand it all, you see.
So why...
I'm afraid.
Afraid?
Of changing the routine of my life.
If I change it, something unforeseen could happen.
Even when my father keeled over, nobody told me to change my lifestyle.
I realize it's no good to keep living as I am, but I still want to.
I don't want to log out.
Even though I know it can't happen,
I'm still thinking that one day, suddenly,
an amazing surprise will occur and everything will start going smoothly.
That feeling... Even I...
Don't you dare understand it!
You can still turn back. Don't end up like me.
Before you drag the people around you into your misfortune,
you have to log out.
Permanently.
Goodbye.
Logged Out.
I'm going home.
Right...
Sorry for the intrusion.
Goodbye.
He's crying.
Sa-Sato...
Thanks for coming shopping with me today.
I still don't understand things in this world very well.
So, I want you to choose which clothes look good on me.
Huh? This one? Wait a minute. I'll try it on, okay?
Well? Does it look good?
Really? Great! Okay, starting next time, I'll appear in this outfit.
Wow...
What's this about?
This is an event scene that appears after you've cleared the game.
You can choose the heroine's default outfit for the next game here.
It's a little gimmick to keep people from getting bored after the first time.
Wow... A lot of thinking goes into this, huh?
But when the main narrative still isn't finished, there isn't any point creating stuff like this, is there?
Whose fault do you think it is that it's not finished?
My work is at a halt because your scenario isn't progressing at all!
I can't do anything else but make this kind of stuff!
I want to get started on the work for the main narrative too!
Desperately!
I get it! I'm telling you, I get it!
No, you don't get it!
So, today's the day I'll speak my mind!
Sato, after that hubbub with the pyramid scam, what did you say?
I've had a change of heart.
I vow to seriously devote myself to game creation!
How many weeks do you think have passed since then?
It's been four weeks! Four weeks!
But still the script hasn't progressed by more than a few kilobytes!
We've passed the two-months-left point for the winter Comic Stall!
And this time we can't get away with faking it with some sample!
This is the moment of truth for you too, Sato,
to show whether you can carve out a life as a game creator or not!
Oh, is it this late already?
It... It's open...
Um, if I'm intruding, it can wait till later.
It's fine. Please feed Sato.
Tuna again?
It's because the compound DHA found in tuna stimulates brain activity.
I believe that eating tuna will unquestionably have a positive effect on your creative activities.
If eating tuna made me able to write the script, I wouldn't be having so much trouble.
No complaining.
Who do you have to thank, Sato, for the fact that even though your allowance has been cut in half,
you're not starving to death?
Well, it's not really like I begged you to...
So, you'd be okay with starving?
Or do you want to get swamped by debt, like that committee-girl from your high school?
Thank you for this meal.
Certainly.
At Yuuhiyama Zoo, which has been a major topic of late,
a new animal exhibit has opened starting today...
Hey, what was it called?
That pyramid scheme company that you "cooled off" from?
Huh? Oh...
This just in.
The headquarters of a company previously suspected of being a disreputable pyramid scheme,
What was it...
"My"...
Mouseroad, has been raided by the Tokyo prosecutor's office,
Uh, I'm here at the Tokyo headquarters of Mouseroad,
That's it.
Mouseroad...
The Tokyo prosecutor's office has raided Mouseroad,
What?!
That's hot!
previously suspected of...
I-I'm sorry!
Something to wipe with... quick!
Here!
It's hot...
It's hot!
Sato, are you watching the news?!
Mouseroad...
Sorry to intrude!
Huh?
Wait, Yamazaki!
Furthermore, reports say that the total number of Mouseroad members in Tokyo is over 15,000,
You've got it all wrong!
Now, on to Mouseroad, where a raid has been ongoing for some days.
Today, investigators again entered the home of executive Sukekiyo Sagawa,
where a foreign-made luxury car and other items were seized.
[ I'm hungry! I'm hungry! I'm hungry! ]
What are you doing, Megumi?
What's happening with my food?
I haven't eaten for three days.
Megumi!
Am I just going to die like this?
Big brother, I'm sorry I've been away for days.
There's been a bit of trouble.
Are you hungry? I'll make something right now.
Big brother?
Big brother? Big brother!
I'm telling you!
The heroine's emotional line here is weird!
It is? I don't really think it's weird.
It's no good!
Players won't find this kind of thing satisfying!
You can say that, but we only have one month until the winter Stall!
There's no time to be fixing it now!
Huh?
What is it?
It's from the Class Rep.
Mouseroad should be history by now, right?
I wonder if she's going to ask you to join a different pyramid scam?
Hello? Yeah, it's me.
What? Are you serious?
She said Toro Toro's gone missing!
What?!
I already tried everywhere I could think of!
You were the only one left, Sato.
I see, so he hasn't contacted you either then.
Yeah, I'll inform the police too,
but if you get an e-mail or anything, please let me know!
I look horrible...
What will I do now?
Shall I go back to school?
Right, the pork-rice meal and tempura-rice meal are up.
I'm going out on delivery.
Be careful while you're out.
That boy's gotten a lot more energetic, huh?
What do you mean "boy"?
He's a man of plenty of years.
But when he first came to this shop, he looked just like a ghost.
Saying stuff like, "I'll do anything if you'll give me food to eat."
What's more, he said he was a hikikomori, right?
He said he'd never actually worked in his life, which worried me.
You know what they say: "A person does what he's got to do."
If they get hungry, human beings will work.
Episode 19
Welcome to the Blue Bird!
Thank you!
Even if this world
moshimo ashita kono sekai ga
were to end tomorrow, since it's you,
owaru to shite mo kimi no koto dakara
would you take the curt attitude of
sore nara sore demo iika
"If so, that's okay with me"?
sokkenai taido toru no kana
There's no need to strain yourself.
muri suru koto wa dakedo
Just sometimes would be fine, so lift up your face
tama ni demo iikara kao wo agete
and look this way.
kocchi wo miteyo
Look at me.
watashi wo mite
Though it's a tiny world,
chippoke na sekai nanoni
for some reason it's too big for these two hands.
naze darou kono ryoute ni wa ooki sugiru
Though it's an endless world,
hateshinai sekai nanoni
for some reason it's too small for these two hands.
naze darou kono ryoute ni wa chiisa sugiru
Hey,
nee modokashii
in the brilliant morning light
asa no hikari no naka de
I want to laugh with you.
kimi to warai tai
What's the name of the star?
A person's life is no more than trash, I guess.
Do you think you're God or something?!
Next Episode
Welcome to Winter Days!
Next episode, "Welcome to Winter Days!"