I lift my eyes a little and look into the sky
sukoshi miageta sora
All I do is mutter every time,
dekisugita nichijou
as I turn my back
se wo mukeru tabi ni
on this perfect everyday life
tsubuyaku dake
"Where am I supposed to go?"
doko ni ikeba ii no
With you who are giving me a look like that?
sonna kao shiteru kimi to
In the shadows of a back alley,
rojiura no kage tokei no hari ga
the hands of a clock repaint the time that has been stopped.
tomatta jikan wo nurikaete
Extended hands,
sashinobeta ryoute
puzzle pieces that don't fit.
kamiawanai pazuru wo
Until the abandoned two
okizari ni shiteta
reunite with something
futari deau made
that has been lost.
nakushiteta nanika
Recover
saigo no kakera wo
the last piece,
torimodoshite
and let's start walking.
arukidasou
I think we need to be more forward about dating women.
Now, don't get me wrong.
I don't mean that in a weird way.
It's just that every experience is food for thought for a game creator.
That's the opposite of what you were saying before, right?
Dates, for example.
For portraying a dating scene,
if we don't know what a real date is like, we won't get anywhere.
A real date...
Watching fireworks...
Walking together a little...
I wonder if I'm supposed to buy her something at times like that?!
Thanks!
Here!
Thanks, Sato.
Why didn't you buy her something then?
You had enough money for that, right?!
That cotton candy might have led to...
Tatsuhiro Sato, that was the blunder of a lifetime!
Sato...
Just write the script, okay?
The fact is, I know too little about her,
about Misaki.
What she likes, what she doesn't like,
what kinds of things she likes someone to do for her.
Sato, please show me what you wrote today.
I'll check it.
Huh? It's only just past noon, right?
I'm supposed to meet somebody.
Truth is, it's a date.
No big deal; this girl insists she wants to see a movie with me.
It's really just a "gathering data for our game" type thing.
There, I sent it.
Dreams and hopes...
Sato...
What?
The heroine's name is wrong.
Huh?
In which part?
Well, it's not just one part...
Misaki
"Good morning, Misaki."
"What's wrong, Misaki?"
"I trust you, Misaki."
"I want to keep a smile on your face, Misaki."
"Misaki, I could die for you."
The heroine's name is "Rei," you know.
What are you doing?! Sato! Hey!
I'm... I'm giving up writing!
What?!
The kind of guy who gets the heroine's name wrong has no right to call himself a scriptwriter!
I'll annihilate the script and the computer too!
This is my computer!
Don't wig out like that!
Misaki
If you just change the name, it's usable as a script.
And I'll tell her...
"...I don't understand..."
Misaki
Misaki Hakahara
Her hands were soft, and small.
Four more hours...
It's not like I can see her sooner if I go early.
But...
What the heck...
I just feel like going out a little earlier today.
That's it. That's all it is.
I'll give you some food now, okay?
Here.
You're awfully early, huh?
So are you, Sato.
I just happened to pass by while I was out for a walk.
You're such a fibber.
What?
You're a hikikomori, Sato. There's no way you'd go for walks.
Cats are great, aren't they?
What's great about them?
They just seem so calm,
all the time, wherever they are; even if they're alone.
Cats are pretty ungrateful, you know.
Even if you give it food, it'll immediately forget all about you, Misaki.
Yikes! That was too cynical!
I didn't intend to say things like that!
It's all right.
As long as I'm giving it what it wants, I'm sure it will remember me.
Meow.
Well now, shall we get started?
You're a troubled person. You're in pain.
I feel bad for how you're suffering.
But keep your chin up when you walk. You're fine as you are.
You have dreams, so you'll be fine. You're not alone.
If you just walk, a path will be there. Everyone's pulling for you.
You're trying, and that makes you shine.
Just think positively, and it will be okay.
We'll move together towards tomorrow. The future will be great.
You're a troubled person. You're a troubled person.
That's all for today.
Oh, okay.
Were you listening?
Of... Of course. No, I mean...
What if I said I wasn't listening carefully? And that I want you to start over from the beginning?
If we start from the beginning, it will get too late.
But maybe from the middle...
Just joking! Truth is, I was listening carefully.
Hey! We're talking about something serious!
Next time you make a joke like that, you'll owe me a million yen.
All right, I understand.
I can't get Misaki's face out of my head.
I've never thought about the future,
but maybe I could...
With her...
Come to think of it...
I haven't heard anything about Misaki's parents or friends.
She said her grandmother was a prima donna, married to a Frenchman.
That sounds like an outright lie.
What do I know about Misaki?
Nothing has changed since the first time we met.
Who is Misaki?
And why did she approach me?
I don't know anything.
Sato, wake up, please! Sato! Sato!
Hey!
Hey! Do you know what time it is?!
To a game creator, day and night mean nothing.
Sato, this is no time for you to be sleeping.
That's right, it's no time to be sleeping.
Hey...
There's no time left before the Comic Stall.
No time to rest.
Did something happen?
Nothing at all!
The theories I've held for so long
just got proven brilliantly.
Women lie with a straight face.
They're laughing at us guys behind our backs.
Yamazaki...
Why the heck would another guy be at our meeting-spot for a date?
She didn't really expect me to believe that excuse about "happening to bump into him"?
Who'd believe that excuse?
I get it, I get it.
Sato, don't you ever let your guard down with women either.
They're always plotting something behind your back.
There are certainly too many mysteries about Misaki.
I know.
You come to this park every Sunday night and do nothing but gaze into space, right?
Why does she know my activity patterns?
But other than that, you don't go outside at all.
Date of birth, January 28th, Aquarius.
Blood type A.
Why does she know so much about me?
You were born in Hokkaido.
Won't you come with me to see the fireworks?
Why is she so kind to me?
What is she really after?
What do you think, Sato?
Are you suspecting that I'm plotting something?
Shall I tell you why I'm being kind to you, Sato?
It's because I want you to...
I want you to...
to stay a hikikomori forever.
Conspiracy...
Damn! A trap?!
You slipped up, Sato!
You evil wench! You're a secret operative with the Nihon Hikikomori Kyokai!
Most certainly.
My mission is to tempt the world's men with sex appeal and drag them into the hikikomori world.
I'll never let you escape, Sato.
No! I'll get away! You watch!
Not a chance!
After all, Sato...
You love me, don't you?
No! I don't!
You love me, don't you, Sato?
No...
Who could ever love someone like...
Yamazaki...
Good morning, Sato.
Did I say something to you last night?
No.
I hope not.
Seems like I drank too much, so my memory is spotty in places.
Owww...
Hold on a second, please. We'll get to work right away.
Would you take a little walk with me or something instead?
This is unusual, for you to say of your own accord that you want to go out, Sato.
Oh, it's that girl.
You're not going in?
No.
How long are we going to wait?
Sure could use some ice cream.
Hi there.
Do you think it's okay to do this kind of thing?
It's unfair that I know nothing about her, isn't it,
when she's even met my mother?
Could that mansion be her house?
Hey, hold on!
From this place,
that park where we always meet is right in front of her eyes.
Chiba
Sato, this is bad!
Our apartments are in plain view from here!
What?
Could it be that she was watching me?
This whole time, up until now?
Why is it so darn hot like this? I'm getting so tired of it.
Oh no!
Well, let's go.
I seem to recall that the group who publishes those solicitation brochures rents that building.
I wonder if it's a meeting or something?
That's right.
Today was great, wasn't it?
It really was. My heart has been cleansed.
We're going, Misaki.
You're not going to follow her, Sato?
That's enough.
The girl's a member of a questionable group,
and she was watching me this whole time.
But I still feel... Misaki...
That's right, wake up!
This is a conspiracy, Sato.
It's a conspiracy by the Nihon Hikikomori Kyokai!
One to keep you a hikikomori for your whole life.
But Misaki said she was going to get me out of the hikikomori life!
That's what's scary about this conspiracy.
They seduce you with those kind of nice words...
and when they've made you a prisoner of the fantasy of love...
...what they do is smash that fantasy to bits.
The psychological damage you suffer will probably be immeasurable, Sato.
You'll be unable to trust...
Any woman...
Any human being at all...
And you'll become incapable of ever going out again.
You'll have to...
remain a hikikomori...
...forever.
Forever...
Forever. Forever.
So, what am I supposed to do?!
Just don't see her.
If you don't see her, you won't fall in love.
If you don't fall in love...
you won't get hurt.
We're warning you...
This Misaki Nakahara...
you must never...
see her again.
That's it.
If I do it now, I can still turn back.
If I fall for her any more,
then if she were to betray me,
I would...
You... you're late.
Okay, I'm going to start today's lecture.
I'm quitting counseling.
Because you've gotten too busy with the game script?
I don't ever want to see your face again!
Episode 10
Welcome to the Dark Side!
Was that the right thing to do?
Ababa, ababa, ababa, dancing baby human!
ababa ababa ababa odoru akachan ningen hogya
When we were born naked,
hito wa hadaka de umareta toki wa
we were all loved equally, just as it's supposed to be.
dare mo aisare onajina hazu ga
But why, as life goes on,
doushite nano da ikite iku uchi
does each destiny take a different path? It's almost cruel.
sadame wa wakare mugoi kurai da
Some can look at other's eyes, while others can't.
hito no me mitari mirenakattari
Some get to learn love, while others don't.
koi wo shittari shirenakattari
If that's how it is, I'd rather be
sore nara boku wa isso naritai
a baby, a baby human till I die.
shinu made baby akachan ningen
"Oh, what an adorable baby!"
Ah, nante kawaii baby
"I just want to love you!"
aishitaku naru wa
(Just like I planned!)
omou tsubo daze
(It worked perfectly!)
umaku ittaze
The baby she's holding isn't really a baby human.
kanojo daita akago jitsu wa akachan ningen
"Ababa!" I snicker to myself, hiding in my pretended innocence.
adokenasa no ura de ababa hokusoemu no sa
It's so easy to be a baby human, so you should be one too!
kimi mo nare yo raku de iize baby human
Ababa, ababa! Dance, multiply, and take it to space!
ababa ababa odore fuyase soshite uchuu e
To Mars! To Saturn! To the galaxy! Dance! Baby human!
kasei e dosei e ginga e odoru yo akachan ningen
Dance! Baby human!
odoru yo akachan ningen
What did I do wrong?
My life as a hikikomori is over.
You won't have any regrets, will you, Sato?
Next Episode
Welcome to the Conspiracy!
Next episode, "Welcome to the Conspiracy!"