I lift my eyes a little and look into the sky
sukoshi miageta sora
All I do is mutter every time,
dekisugita nichijou
as I turn my back
se wo mukeru tabi ni
on this perfect everyday life
tsubuyaku dake
"Where am I supposed to go?"
doko ni ikeba ii no
With you who are giving me a look like that?
sonna kao shiteru kimi to
In the shadows of a back alley,
rojiura no kage tokei no hari ga
the hands of a clock repaint the time that has been stopped.
tomatta jikan wo nurikaete
Extended hands,
sashinobeta ryoute
puzzle pieces that don't fit.
kamiawanai pazuru wo
Until the abandoned two
okizari ni shiteta
reunite with something
futari deau made
that has been lost.
nakushiteta nanika
Recover
saigo no kakera wo
the last piece,
torimodoshite
and let's start walking.
arukidasou
間違いない。
これは...
陰謀
陰謀だ！
そうだ、俺は...
俺は大きな陰謀に...
陰謀の...
途轍もなく巨大な陰謀に...
A dream and a conspiracy...
陰謀に...
巻き込まれてしまったのだ!
...magical girl, that is me!
どうも（？）最近頭の調子は悪い...
一日１６時間も寝ているからだろうか?
隣の部屋から今日も美少女のアニメI can hear the theme song of a girlie anime blasting through from next door again.
This has been going on every single day since last month.
Yeah, I already know...
I've heard that phrase hundreds of times.
But at any rate, I don't know about this "pururin" thing.
Is she a bouncy-looking girl or something?
That's not a human!
Or does it mean a girl that looks like a pudding?
Quiet!
Shut up!
Today's the day! I'm not going to take this anymore!
I hate this song! If I have to keep listening to it, I'm going to go crazy!
I'm going to go complain!
This is no big deal.
In fact, it's pretty simple.
I just have to open the door and walk a few steps towards the next door.
And then I'd knock, open the door and...
You frickin' anime otaku! Turn that shit down!
Just like that, I'd yell at him.
That's all there is to it.
That's all I have to do!
There must be something wrong with that person.
I heard voices...
Doesn't he have any sense of shame?
It's just creepy!
So stupid.
I just want him to stop walking around the neighborhood.
Eeeew! What a freak!
So irritating!
Give me a break!
That was my first summer in college.
I was on my way to school and it was scorching hot outside.
I ran back to my apartment as if I were running away from it all.
And from that day forward, I stopped going outside.
Welcome to Garden Mania.
Today we're going to talk about goldenrod.
Conspiracy...
Conspiracy... Conspiracy... Conspiracy...
Conspiracy?!
There are conspiracies in this world.
The Columbia disaster was a Venusian conspiracy.
That's right, she was saying the same thing.
Brown-dyed hair is the beauty industry's conspiracy.
That's right, the existence of conspiracy is talked about in society as if it were true.
Cedar pollen is the facial tissue industry's conspiracy...
But, Senpai.
Ninety-nine percent of all so-called "conspiracies" are simply imagination.
Or they're just big intentional lies.
Basically, they're a bunch of baloney.
So one percent of it is the truth?
I saw a junior student being bullied.
He was a student from the middle school division.
I wanted to show off in front of her.
Conspiracy...
Hey, stop it!
Conspiracy... Conspiracy...
Tell me something, Senpai.
Is this some kind of conspiracy too?
Stop talking!
Homeroom isn't over yet!
Quiet please!
You're the noisiest one!
Sato!
If you have something to say, raise your hand!
Was that a conspiracy too?
This is a conspiracy too...
This is too...
This is too!
Are they all conspiracies?
A dream and a conspiracy
Magical girl
Conspiracy!
I get it!
I must've gotten myself involved in a real, less than one percent probable, conspiracy!
Congratulations, Sato!
So you finally realized, huh?
Yeah...
Things continuously going wrong for you
was in fact a conspiracy to make you withdraw from society!
But who would plot a conspiracy like that?
Conspiracy radio waves!
What's the matter, TV?
It's the N.H.K.!
That evil secret organization N.H.K. is attacking us!
N.H.K.?
Animated by Nakajima SHIGEO
Metamorphic Magical Girl Pururin
I see!
Why didn't I realize such a simple thing until now?
You can't talk about anime without mentioning otaku.
And otaku tend to be anti-social.
People like that eventually become reclusive.
In other words,
they have been mass-producing anime otaku by showing them interesting anime,
helping to create a massive emergence of NEETs!
Basically, N.H.K. is...
JAPAN
SOCIAL-WITHDRAWAL
ASSOCIATION
Nihon Hikikomori Kyokai!
I am the man who became aware of the N.H.K.'s conspiracy:
Sato Tatsuhiro, 22 years old!
I've shut myself away from society for three years...
Almost four years now!
Some karate masters would seclude themselves in the mountains
in order to master the secret technique that could break rocks.
If I can obtain strength by secluding myself,
I should have cultivated enough strength to crush this beer bottle by now.
Who broke the beer bottle?
It was me!
It hurts! It hurts! It hurts! Where's the first aid kit?
Oww!
Oh, before that, I'd better do something about these shards!
Come on, calm down!
First I have to clean up the shards, then treat this wound and...
Get lost! I'm too busy right now!
First of all, I'm a NEET!
Why would a NEET randomly make an appearance anyway?
Wait, could it be the utility bill collector?
Damn, I haven't sent them money for a while.
If they turn off my electricity,
I won't be able to live my NEET life comfortably anymore!
That's a big problem!
Y-Yes!
Jeez, I know they heard me!
Coming!
Huh?
Oh! I didn't know you were in there!
We're sorry to bother you, but...
A-Are you all right?
Your face is bleeding!
I-I-I'm fine.
O-Okay...
Oh, we've been distributing this pamphlet for free.
The Time is Already Here!
Wake up! "Hikikomori" Special Report.
NEET Population on the Rise
Are You Okay?
It's this month's special article.
Have you ever heard of NEETs before?
It's about the people who shut themselves away from society, refusing to go to school or work.
It's become a serious social issue these days...
Does this lady know that I've been shutting myself away from society?
Is it possible that I'm a well-known NEET in this town?
Is that it?!
Would you be interested in this?
If so, please take a look at it and...
Me? A NEET?! Give me a break!
All right, supposedly I haven't talked to anyone for almost a year.
Yeah, I dropped out of the college because of my social withdrawal trait!
And of course I'm unemployed!
To make matters worse, I have no hope for the future!
Yeah, right!
"Are you okay?"
Hell yeah, I'm okay, thank you very much!
I...
No one would go through this pain if a little prayer could fix it!
What can you possibly understand about it,
when I can't understand a damn thing about it myself!
You would never understand it!
Misaki! Come on, let's go.
What are you doing?
Misaki!
As a matter of fact, I do know what I should be doing about it.
I should get out there right now and find a part-time job or anything.
And if I did that, that rumor about a NEET living in this room would be just a lie.
Then, I'm sure that girl would think I just happened to be home because I was off today too.
Misaki...
I've got a handkerchief, pocket tissues, my wallet and my resume.
I've heard that you guys are hiring... I've heard that you guys are hiring...
I've heard that you guys are hiring...
All right!
Excuse me, um...
I've heard that... you...
you...
You?
You...
"I've heard that you..." What?
Y-Y-You...
You like motorcycles? I do!
You can become the wind, you know. There's nothing like the sound of that engine!
Wanna go for a ride together? What do you think?
But to tell you the truth, I've never even ridden a bike before! Yup!
Err...
Okay, bye.
I'm gonna kill myself!
But I already know that I can't kill myself like this.
Because I'll just pass out
and my grip will weaken before I die.
Why was she, of all girls, there?
Should a servant of God be working a part-time job?
No, I guess even a servant of God needs money.
After all, she's just flesh and blood.
That's right, she's flesh and blood.
I shouldn't! I shouldn't be doing this!
No!
I shouldn't!
God is watching me!
Now that I think about it,
there's no way the utility company would actually send someone to my house
to collect outstanding bills from me nowadays.
So, ignoring this won't affect my life in any way.
In fact, I should ignore it.
Because I carelessly opened the door yesterday,
I was... I was...
That girl...
RESUME ENCLOSED
Did she come all the way to drop this off for me?
To Tatsuhiro Sato,
You have been chosen for my project.
Therefore, please come to Mita Park on 4th Street at 9:00 tonight,
Misaki Nakahara.
If this is about soliciting me for her religion, she's not doing a good job at all.
It's hard to believe anyone would fall for this.
But at the same time, this is how they get you.
Using young girls to lure young men...
It's an old trick.
She must be a promiscuous girl.
Why would I fall for a girl like that?
Sato!
Come to me, Sato.
This is ridiculous!
Please come to Mita Park on 4th Street at 9:00 tonight,
Actually, that park is the only place I can relax outside of this room.
And I was thinking about going to the park to relax tonight.
I shouldn't let some bizarre letter like that interfere with my schedule.
That's right.
I was already planning to go to the park!
I realized that I overlooked one big possibility in all this.
It's possible that the letter was just a joke.
If that's the case, I'm the biggest clown for being here right now.
What am I saying?!
I was already planning to come here anyway!
Why did you run away this afternoon?
I was going to hire you right then and there because we've been short-staffed.
Did you get scared of going outside and working?
Since you're a hikikomori?
But I'm sure you'll be fine.
Because I know how to get you out of it.
Huh?
Besides, I've known about you for a long time.
I've come to rescue you.
Project
Episode 01
Welcome to the Project!
Ababa, ababa, ababa, dancing baby human!
ababa ababa ababa odoru akachan ningen hogya
When we were born naked,
hito wa hadaka de umareta toki wa
we were all loved equally, just as it's supposed to be.
dare mo aisare onajina hazu ga
But why, as life goes on,
doushite nano da ikite iku uchi
does each destiny take a different path? It's almost cruel.
sadame wa wakare mugoi kurai da
Some can look at other's eyes, while others can't.
hito no me mitari mirenakattari
Some get to learn love, while others don't.
koi wo shittari shirenakattari
If that's how it is, I'd rather be
sore nara boku wa isso naritai
a baby, a baby human till I die.
shinu made baby akachan ningen
"Oh, what an adorable baby!"
Ah, nante kawaii baby
"I just want to love you!"
aishitaku naru wa
(Just like I planned!)
omou tsubo daze
(It worked perfectly!)
umaku ittaze
The baby she's holding isn't really a baby human.
kanojo daita akago jitsu wa akachan ningen
"Ababa!" I snicker to myself, hiding in my pretended innocence.
adokenasa no ura de ababa hokusoemu no sa
It's so easy to be a baby human, so you should be one too!
kimi mo nare yo raku de iize baby human
Ababa, ababa! Dance, multiply, and take it to space!
ababa ababa odore fuyase soshite uchuu e
To Mars! To Saturn! To the galaxy! Dance! Baby human!
kasei e dosei e ginga e odoru yo akachan ningen
Dance! Baby human!
odoru yo akachan ningen
I mustn't run away!
This is Hitomi's request.
You can write the script, can't you?!
Next Episode
Welcome to the Creator!