I lift my eyes a little and look into the sky
sukoshi miageta sora
All I do is mutter every time,
dekisugita nichijou
as I turn my back
se wo mukeru tabi ni
on this perfect everyday life
tsubuyaku dake
"Where am I supposed to go?"
doko ni ikeba ii no
With you who are giving me a look like that?
sonna kao shiteru kimi to
In the shadows of a back alley,
rojiura no kage tokei no hari ga
the hands of a clock repaint the time that has been stopped.
tomatta jikan wo nurikaete
Extended hands,
sashinobeta ryoute
puzzle pieces that don't fit.
kamiawanai pazuru wo
Until the abandoned two
okizari ni shiteta
reunite with something
futari deau made
that has been lost.
nakushiteta nanika
Recover
saigo no kakera wo
the last piece,
torimodoshite
and let's start walking.
arukidasou
I see, you went to a school in the middle of the city, huh?
You, a hikikomori, actually went to a place with lots of people.
That's big progress, Sato!
I know, I'm impressed myself.
I might as well say that my hikikomori condition has been cured.
Now you should be fine going outside by yourself, huh?
Of course.
Well then!
See ya!
Wh-What is this?
Oh yeah, I'm not hikikomori anymore!
All right!
Kokogi Designer Institute
I'm going to school!
Good morning!
Introduction
Development
Turn in
Conclusion
Good morning, Sato!
You know the project is due today, right?
Yup! I got it right here!
That's my Sato!
But...
It looks like your work is pretty amateurish actually.
Damn it! Is it a trap?!
Eject!
So, it was them behind this all along.
I'm the victim of a conspiracy plotted by the Nihon Hikikomori Kyokai!
St-Stay away from me!
Stay away from me!
Sato, I'm coming in!
Huh? Yeah...
Sorry to have you do this every day.
Don't worry about it.
After all, you've been paying for my services.
People always say that summer colds take a long time to get over,
but you really have been sick for a long time.
How are you feeling?
It's like, my body still feels sluggish.
At first, I thought your hikikomori condition got worse.
That can't be.
Remember, I went to your school the other day by myself.
I know.
Well, take care now.
I'm a big liar.
This is a conspiracy plotted by the Nihon Hikikomori Kyokai!
Ever since I visited Yamazaki's school,
my hikikomori condition has gotten much worse.
I don't want to see anyone.
I don't even want to answer my cell phone.
I don't want to do anything.
I don't want to even live.
But dying is a pain in the ass too.
I wish I could just disappear.
I wonder what would have happened to me if Yamazaki had never come to check on me?
I just lied to Yamazaki saying I had a summer cold.
But I'm sure he's going to find out that's a lie sooner or later.
What the hell am I supposed to do now?
Fight, Sato! Fight against the enemy's conspiracy!
Enemy?
That's right! Our common enemy!
N.H.K.!
You must fight against the conspiracy plotted by the Nihon Hikikomori Kyokai!
Fight against them? But I don't have any weapons.
You do have weapons!
That's right!
Love and courage!
But I don't have love or courage.
A phone call! A phone call!
Huh? This is certainly unusual. Telephone's calling you!
I wonder if there's been some kind of accident or something?
A phone call! A phone call!
Telephone?
A phone call!
RECORDING...
Sorry, I'm not available to take your call.
Please leave a message after the beep.
If you wish to send me a fax, please press your send button now.
Hello? It's Mom.
Tatsuhiro, are you there?
Mom?
I have some business in Tokyo, so I'm coming up there.
I was thinking I should drop by and see you while I'm there.
And we could discuss your future plans and stuff then too.
RECORDING...
I'll talk to you later!
Mom's coming here?!
Discuss my future plans?!
Is she planning to make me move back home?!
Give me a freakin' break!
After everything I've done to move to Tokyo?!
I'd just be a loser if I move back home!
What should I do?
Yes, hello?
Tatsuhiro? Oh, you're home!
Damn! I answered it!
If you're home, answer the phone, all right?
Oh, I just came back in.
Really? Then I guess you still haven't checked your message,
but my class reunion is coming up on Saturday.
Three days from today?!
And it looks like I'll have some free time the day before the reunion,
so I want to see you and discuss some things!
Two days from today?!
You can't just keep on wasting your time doing nothing in Tokyo forever, you know.
Isn't it time for you to come back home and get a job down here?
Here it comes!
Besides you'll never be able to get married at this rate.
But I'm fine, you know!
What?
Actually, I've already found a job.
It's a small software company, but I've been writing scripts and stuff for them.
And I haven't told you this,
but there's someone I'm considering getting married to as well.
So, I've pretty much decided on settling down here in Tokyo.
Well, good for you, Tatsuhiro!
I've been so worried about you.
But good, you've got a job now and you're getting married.
Well, the marriage part isn't gonna happen anytime soon.
You see, they don't pay you a whole lot when you start a new job.
That's all right! Just knowing that you've got a girlfriend is such a relief!
You have to let me meet her when I come to Tokyo, all right?
Yeah, sure.
Okay, then I'll call you again with the flight information and stuff!
Goodnight!
IN USE
Goodnight...
Don't buy into it so easily.
Can't you tell it's a lie?
Software company... script writing...
Come on, be more suspicious!
Stop being so happy!
Mom...
M-Mom?
Huh? Oh, wait...
Err, it's not Mom?
Is this Mr. Tatsuhiro Sato's residence?
Yes.
So, this is the right number then.
Hey, I've been worried about you.
You haven't shown up for counseling or answered your cell phone.
Is this Misaki?!
One million yen penalty!
Wait, I have a really good reason for this whole thing!
First of all, I have a more important thing to worry about right now!
What kind of thing?
Well, I just found out that my mother is coming to Tokyo.
Your mother?
So, you told her you've got a job at a promising company
and a girlfriend who's going to marry you.
There are limits to how much you should make up.
What was I supposed to do?!
She was planning to drag me back home unless I told her stuff like that!
I have two more days before she comes.
I have to come up with a way to fool her before that!
A company and a girlfriend...
A girlfriend...
I guess I have no choice, do I, Sato?
I don't mind pretending to be your girlfriend for a day if you want me to.
Oh, yeah, there's Yamazaki!
I just have to ask Yamazaki!
Ya-Yamazaki is going to be your girlfriend?!
You can't do that! No way!
I have no time to waste! I'm gonna ask Yamazaki right now!
W-Wait!
Sato!
Nanako...
Yamazaki! Yamazaki!
Yes?
A company! We're gonna make a company, Yamazaki!
Wh-What are you doing?
Company?
If I remember correctly,
you can establish a company with as little as one yen capital these days!
If we establish a company, I can fool my mother!
Wait, we were gonna make the world's preeminent game company to begin with anyway!
It's just that our plan has been accelerated a little!
We're are going to proudly bring our own brand to the game industry, Yamazaki!
Our brand...
That sounds great! Let's do it!
LET'S MAKE A COMPANY!
LET'S PICK A COMPANY NAME
Let's pick a company name!
First, let's pick a company name!
Why don't we take "Sa" from Sato and '"Yama" from Yamazaki
and call it "Sayama Company"! How's that?
But then it sounds like a person named Sayama founded the company.
You're right.
Then what about something non-Japanese...
How's that?!
I can't memorize all that!
LET'S MAKE A COMPANY LOGO
Let's make a company logo!
Okay, for now let's say that our company name is '"Y.S. Company."
I'm not happy with the name either, so let's change it once we become big!
Next up is the company logo!
Since it's "Y.S.", how about something like this?
Hey, it looks like a logo on the baseball cap for some baseball team.
I mean, for now, just for now.
LET'S MAKE A COMPANY SONG
Let's make a company song!
Company song! Company song! Company song for Y.S.!
LET'S MAKE BUSINESS CARDS
Let's make business cards!
There!
President: Kaoru Yamazaki
Y.S. Company Limited
President, eh?
I'm jealous...
I'd love to call myself "co-president,"
but I've already told my mother that I found a job, so...
Don't worry!
I've got a job title that's perfect for you!
NEET: Tatsuhiro Sato
Y.S. Company Limited
NEET?
That explains your current status in on simple word, doesn't it?
I'm working hard so that she doesn't find out that's what I am, you jerk!
First of all, NEET isn't a business title!
LET'S MAKE A RECEPTION DESK
Let's make a reception desk!
The reception desk is the face of the company!
Therefore, we're going to ask her to be the receptionist for our company!
What?
Welcome
Reception Desk
Now our company is perfect!
Bring it on, Mother!
Sato...
Are you really going to show this to your mother?
Basically, at the very least,
what we need is for it to appear as though our company is legit, right?
Because you don't really want to bring her to this room.
That's for sure...
Tatsuhiro Sato
Y.S. Company Limited
I think she'll be convinced if I show this business card to her.
Excuse me...
How are you going to fool her about the girlfriend who's going to marry you?
Oh, damn!
I forgot about that problem!
If you want me to, I can pretend to be your girlfriend for a day.
Huh?
Kashiwa Hitomi
I'm sure Senpai will help me out on this one if I explain the situation!
Besides, it's possible that something intended as a lie could come true too!
Hello? Senpai? It's Sato.
The day after tomorrow?
I'm sorry, but I already have plans.
Yeah, I have an appointment with my friend.
Oh, I see.
No, that's fine.
Yes.
Talk to you later.
My only hope...
Now that it's come to this, I guess I'll have Yamazaki dress in drag.
Nice to meet you, Mother! I'm Kaoru Yamazaki!
Hell no...
I won't be able to take it.
I can do it for you, you know,
play your girlfriend.
Huh?
Why?
Why did this happen?
Hey, you're late!
Say, do we really have to do this?
Look, when you lie, it's written all over your face.
If we don't have at least one real date beforehand, she'll be able to tell you're lying right away.
But if I go to some place with a bunch of people, the same thing might happen to me again.
Huh?
If we're together, I'm sure you'll be fine.
I guess this is what a so-called "normal relationship" is.
We should've made it more official and dated each other back then, huh?
Hey, Sato.
Huh?
Wanna try walking arm in arm?
We look more like a real couple that way.
I'm sure we'll look normal.
What is that I'm feeling?!
Could this be the sign?!
Is she coming on to me?!
Is this all right?
Is this lie turning into the truth?!
A-Are you okay?
Next time will be the real deal, huh?
You'd better clean up your apartment, or your mother will be shocked.
Yeah...
Well, I'll see you tomorrow!
Hey, wait!
If we're going to pretend to be a couple,
won't it be a problem if we don't know more about each other?
Your name is about the only thing I know about you, you know.
Oh, really?
Yeah...
Actually, I know you very well, Sato.
Huh?
Name, Tatsuhiro Sato. Date of birth, January 28th, Aquarius.
Blood type A. You were born in Hokkaido.
Your hobby is watching videos.
Oh yeah, and recently you've gotten into gal games and collecting pictures of a "graphic" nature.
The last place you attended school was at Heisei Bunka University, a private school,
but you dropped out.
Your father's name is Tatsuo. Mother's name is Shizue.
Why do you know so much about me?
You told me before.
You forgot?
Did I?
Yeah, I have a good memory.
Is this Mr. Tatsuhiro Sato's residence?
Now that I think about it...
Why does she knows the phone number to my apartment?
The only people I've given that number to are my parents back home.
See ya!
Wait!
You haven't told me anything about yourself yet.
It'll be a problem if I don't know anything about you when my mother asks me, won't it?
Do you really wanna know?
Yeah...
Absolutely?
Yeah.
Okay, I'll tell you, but you have to memorize it.
Yeah!
First, I'll tell you about my family tree.
My grandfather is French and his name is Georges Brufelles.
My grandmother is a Japanese prima donna!
They met at Port Moresby and fell in love. They came back to Japan and got married.
Then my mother was born and she got married to my father, an elite businessman.
Then I was born, but now I live with my relatives due to unavoidable familial circumstances.
How's that? You got it?
S-Sort of...
Then what is my grandfather's name?
John... Brook... Brooklyn?
Wrong! It's Georges Brufelles!
Jeez, you have to remember it by tomorrow. That's your homework!
It's Georges Brufelles, okay?
George Bl... No, Bly...
Hey, it's obviously a lie! What does she mean, he's French?!
Just who is she?
Arrive at Haneda Airport 12:35 PM.
Arrival gate 2.
Pick me up at the airport.
- Mom.
Pick me up at the airport. Mom.
Episode 07
Welcome to the Moratorium!
Ababa, ababa, ababa, dancing baby human!
ababa ababa ababa odoru akachan ningen hogya
When we were born naked,
hito wa hadaka de umareta toki wa
we were all loved equally, just as it's supposed to be.
dare mo aisare onajina hazu ga
But why, as life goes on,
doushite nano da ikite iku uchi
does each destiny take a different path? It's almost cruel.
sadame wa wakare mugoi kurai da
Some can look at other's eyes, while others can't.
hito no me mitari mirenakattari
Some get to learn love, while others don't.
koi wo shittari shirenakattari
If that's how it is, I'd rather be
sore nara boku wa isso naritai
a baby, a baby human till I die.
shinu made baby akachan ningen
"Oh, what an adorable baby!"
Ah, nante kawaii baby
"I just want to love you!"
aishitaku naru wa
(Just like I planned!)
omou tsubo daze
(It worked perfectly!)
umaku ittaze
The baby she's holding isn't really a baby human.
kanojo daita akago jitsu wa akachan ningen
"Ababa!" I snicker to myself, hiding in my pretended innocence.
adokenasa no ura de ababa hokusoemu no sa
It's so easy to be a baby human, so you should be one too!
kimi mo nare yo raku de iize baby human
Ababa, ababa! Dance, multiply, and take it to space!
ababa ababa odore fuyase soshite uchuu e
To Mars! To Saturn! To the galaxy! Dance! Baby human!
kasei e dosei e ginga e odoru yo akachan ningen
Dance! Baby human!
odoru yo akachan ningen
I'm Misaki Nakahara!
Hello, Y.S. Company!
I can't believe a cute girl like her will be my daughter-in-law!
Next episode, "Welcome to Chinatown!"
Next Episode
Welcome to Chinatown!