I lift my eyes a little and look into the sky
sukoshi miageta sora
All I do is mutter every time,
dekisugita nichijou
as I turn my back
se wo mukeru tabi ni
on this perfect everyday life
tsubuyaku dake
"Where am I supposed to go?"
doko ni ikeba ii no
With you who are giving me a look like that?
sonna kao shiteru kimi to
In the shadows of a back alley,
rojiura no kage tokei no hari ga
the hands of a clock repaint the time that has been stopped.
tomatta jikan wo nurikaete
Extended hands,
sashinobeta ryoute
puzzle pieces that don't fit.
kamiawanai pazuru wo
Until the abandoned two
okizari ni shiteta
reunite with something
futari deau made
that has been lost.
nakushiteta nanika
Recover
saigo no kakera wo
the last piece,
torimodoshite
and let's start walking.
arukidasou
Sa-Sato...
Let's go, Mia.
Your friend is there, right? You don't need to logout?
I'll ignore her. If I leave her alone,
she'll go away of her own accord.
As for us, let's enjoy our adventure, Mia.
How did he get like this?
He's had a lot of troubles until now too, but...
And I thought he was generally headed in a positive direction!
I can't believe he's even worse than before!
Sa-Sato...
Let's go outside. I'm sure that would be a positive step.
Hey, the weather's nice out there! So, what do you say?
Sato...
Sa-To?
Huh?
It's nothing at all.
The person in the real world is totally bugging me.
The person who's there wouldn't be your girlfriend, would it?
Don't be ridiculous! I told you, it's just someone I know.
I'm so glad!
That Mia...
You're not...
Sato, with a girl in the game world?
No! That sort of thing is no good! Absolutely not!
I have to do something.
Sato, I'll use my body to pull you back to the world of reality!
Slay a dragon?
You mean us?
Sa-To, you want to do R.M.T., real money trading, right?
Yeah...
If so, you can't get by without slaying dragons.
Dragons usually have all the rare items.
But defeating a dragon at our level would be difficult, wouldn't it?
If we had a Dragon Knight, it'd be different.
Shall we get a Dragon Knight as a companion?
Huh? But I'd rather adventure with just you and me.
I'm not really thinking of staying with a party forever.
We'd just enlist a little help for when we slay the dragon.
I mean, what I want is to get a rare item and see the joy on your face.
Mia...
Well, I'll talk to some people I know. Hold on a minute, okay?
She wants to see the joy on my face, huh?
Sato!
Huh?
What the?!
Meow...
Meow-meow-meow...
Meow, meow-meow-meow, meowmeowmeow-meow! (Please, Sato, come back to your senses!)
Meowmeowmeowmeow-meowmeowmeowmeow, (I'll wear this outfit for you from now on,)
Meowmeowmeowmeowmeow-meow-meow!
(so come out for counseling!)
Meowmeowmeow... (Please...)
Meow? (Okay?)
I have no idea what you're saying!
Meow meow!
What is that outfit supposed to be about?!
B-But Sato,
you were all ga-ga over a girl dressed like this in the game.
Don't you dare make fun of Mia!
My relationship with Mia isn't a matter of appearances like that!
I won't forgive even you, Misaki, if you do a bizarre imitation of it!
Oh my...
If you want to do cosplay, go to a cosplay dance party or something!
What's all the ruckus? Hold it down, huh?
Uh-oh, better get back!
Mia! Mia, where are you?
Sa-To, I'm over here! Look who I brought!
We heard from Mia... It's your first dragon-slaying, huh?
We'll lend you a hand.
Let's all tough this out together.
All of them?
If we have these party members, we'll definitely be able to win!
Thanks, Mia!
Huh?
I hear you want to do R.M.T.? It's hard work.
Everyone says that, but I'll manage. I have tons of time.
Fact is, I'm a hikikomori.
Oh, is that right?
Hey, let's get going, Sa-To!
Right!
It's coming!
That's a dragon!
It's huge...
It's all right. This thing's not as powerful as it looks.
It'll be a cakewalk.
Wings of White, protect my companions!
Regeneration!
Here we go!
What did I get wrong? What was my mistake?
I see...
There's a lot of variety even in this "moe" stuff.
One more push.
Sa-To!
All right!
Black gale, reside in my sword!
Hurricane Blade!
I-I got him.
Oh!
It's Mithril Armor, huh?
We got our hands on a great item.
We can sell that for a lot!
I'm so glad, aren't you, Sa-To?
Hey, look!
This powerful feeling can't be experienced anywhere else, can it?
You're right.
It's wondrous.
It's truly a wondrous world.
Well, I've got work in the real world, so I'm off now.
Yeah, I have to work too.
Give us a call again when an occasion like this comes up.
Thanks, everyone! Thank you!
It'll be great if you're able to R.M.T., won't it, Sa-To?
Huh?
That's, if you're able to.
Logged Out
Do you actually think you can make money that easily?
Big brother, I'm leaving your dinner out here, okay?
For starters, what's up with this character name?
"Sa-To"? That's just his real name as is, right?
Huh? Sato?
That's right, there was a Sato in our class in high school.
I wonder what he's doing now?
This is him.
Tatsuhiro Sato...
Lucky this hut was nearby, huh?
I never imagined it'd suddenly start raining.
Looks like there's a bath inside.
Hey, Sa-To, do you want to take a bath together?
Huh?
I was joking.
Oh, right.
This kind of thing's not bad, huh?
Here we go, Mia!
I'm ready, Sa-To.
Azure Flames, burn away all these enemies!
Spreading Flames!
Sa-To, our combined attack worked!
It did... It worked, huh?
We did it!
Mia, you're my ideal partner.
You're exaggerating...
I've finally realized it.
This world is exactly what I've been seeking for so many long years!
There's not a single thing in the world of reality that has more value than life here!
People in reality spout off all in unison about love and friendship,
but in fact it's a dirty little world full of lies and desires, isn't it?
But in this world, there are genuine adventures into the unknown!
There are also true friends!
Mia!
I think if I'm with you, things will go well for me.
Adventure with me from now until forever!
But I...
If it's about money, I'll earn it through R.M.T. and we'll get by!
So, I'm begging you!
All right...
Mia...
Mia!
Wait!
Eh?
I have just one condition.
Condition?
I want to meet you in reality, Sa-To.
What?
Can I come to your place in the real world?
The real world's not good for me.
What? I can't come?
No, it's not that you can't come...
Really? I'm so glad!
The truth is,
I'm already right in front of your apartment building.
What?
I'm going to climb the apartment stairs now, okay?
What are you talking about?
I can see your apartment now, Sa-To!
What?
She can't possibly be...
I've reached your apartment, Sa-To.
I'm going to knock on the door.
It's not locked, is it?
I'm going to open it now.
Hi...
I'm Mia.
Y-Yamazaki...
How was your adventurous journey with the beautiful cat-eared girl, Sato?
I wanted to teach you what online games are all about,
so I created a character named Mia and was playing with you.
Yamazaki...
Mia's true identity was you?
Sato, it can't be that you thought the real Mia was also a beautiful, young girl like this, can it?
On the Internet, anyone can freely change their name, their age, their gender or their appearance.
"True friends" are nothing but mere illusions.
I-Illusions...
I... I knew that much.
My starting the online game was only for the sake of earning money through R.M.T.
R.M.T., right.
To earn money from R.M.T.,
it's necessary to form a team and use very rigorous means.
It's only an extremely tiny percentage of people who've been able to do that.
For a person like you, Sato, who's easy to fool and has no knowledge of programming,
it's impossible!
But I have a lot of time.
Well, how many years do you plan to keep at it?
Are you going to keep this up for 10 years? For 20 years? For 30 years?
Try picturing what you'll look like 30 years from now!
30 years from now...
Your dreams of R.M.T. shattered, called back to your parents' home...
Picture yourself at 50, supported by your parents!
Tatsuhiro?
Dinner is ready.
Come down to eat for a change!
Give it a rest, you old bag! Don't go bellyachin' about me!
Oh, you need to eat vegetables once in a while.
Leave him be.
He's already 50.
He's too old to have you nattering at him.
But that boy... he's still unemployed, and...
It's too late now. Too late for anything.
I'll tell ya, this harping on stuff whenever they feel like it...
I may not look like much,
but I'm Sa-To, a Level 13,000 Sorcerer-Swordsman!
I'm the hero of Vina Teelo!
I still haven't managed to make any money off R.M.T. though.
You guys...
If I use my magic Confusion, you'll be...
My back...
It's because I put on a little weight recently. Damn...
You'd be the ultimate NEET.
When your parents pass on, your means of survival will be cut off!
That being the case, are you still gonna do R.M.T.?
I'll mention too, that the free trial period is long over,
so you're already in the red.
You're wrong. Somewhere along the way, R.M.T. stopped mattering to me.
I really wanted...
Feelings of romantic love are, in the end, just some chemical reaction.
Under the right conditions, they occur no matter who the other person is.
That's right.
Even if the other person is, for example, me.
Sato, trying to attain something in a game is fruitless.
The ones who make the most money are the people who create the games!
So, let's get back to game creation, with the Winter Comic Stall in mind!
Get out!
What?
Get out of my apartment!
Sato! A game isn't something to play! It's something to create!
My medicine may have had too strong an effect.
What am I supposed to do now?
Hello?
Umm, is this Sato?
Yes...
It's Megumi Kobayashi. We were in the same class in high school.
Kobayashi...
Maybe you don't remember me.
I was on the class committee and stuff.
The class committee...
Oh, the class rep?
Right, right! Do you remember me now?
What's the sudden phone call all about?
Are you having a reunion or something?
Better news than a reunion, maybe.
Huh?
My uniform from when I was in middle school, an apron and homemade food.
With all this, I'm absolutely sure I can pull Sato back to this world.
I'm sure everything'll be fine.
Sato?
Sato!
I'm coming in. It's all right, isn't it?
Sato?
Episode 16
Welcome to Game Over!
Sato?
Even if this world
moshimo ashita kono sekai ga
were to end tomorrow, since it's you,
owaru to shite mo kimi no koto dakara
would you take the curt attitude of
sore nara sore demo iika
"If so, that's okay with me"?
sokkenai taido toru no kana
There's no need to strain yourself.
muri suru koto wa dakedo
Just sometimes would be fine, so lift up your face
tama ni demo iikara kao wo agete
and look this way.
kocchi wo miteyo
Look at me.
watashi wo mite
Though it's a tiny world,
chippoke na sekai nanoni
for some reason it's too big for these two hands.
naze darou kono ryoute ni wa ooki sugiru
Though it's an endless world,
hateshinai sekai nanoni
for some reason it's too small for these two hands.
naze darou kono ryoute ni wa chiisa sugiru
Hey,
nee modokashii
in the brilliant morning light
asa no hikari no naka de
I want to laugh with you.
kimi to warai tai
As if I'd ever play an online game again.
When he gets hungry, he'll come home.
There are no dreams that can't come true!
Next Episode
Welcome to Happiness!
Next episode, "Welcome to Happiness!"