I lift my eyes a little and look into the sky
sukoshi miageta sora
All I do is mutter every time,
dekisugita nichijou
as I turn my back
se wo mukeru tabi ni
on this perfect everyday life
tsubuyaku dake
"Where am I supposed to go?"
doko ni ikeba ii no
With you who are giving me a look like that?
sonna kao shiteru kimi to
In the shadows of a back alley,
rojiura no kage tokei no hari ga
the hands of a clock repaint the time that has been stopped.
tomatta jikan wo nurikaete
Extended hands,
sashinobeta ryoute
puzzle pieces that don't fit.
kamiawanai pazuru wo
Until the abandoned two
okizari ni shiteta
reunite with something
futari deau made
that has been lost.
nakushiteta nanika
Recover
saigo no kakera wo
the last piece,
torimodoshite
and let's start walking.
arukidasou
Big brother...
Don't stare me like that.
You're making me blush, big brother.
I already know...
I know, we're step-brother and sister, aren't we?
But I... Big brother...
Big brother...
I love y...
Y...
Y... Y... Y... Y... Y...
Yucca!
I can't write lines like that!
I had no idea writing a game script could involve this much psychological pressure!
I thought I could write it, if I used some examples, but...
What should I do?
My thing right here is already like this.
What is "like this" anyway?!
Damn it!
No! You have to stop! Otherwise, I will...
Otherwise what?!
Meow!
That's not even Japanese!
I can't do it! I can't write this!
It's men who write these things, right?
I can't believe they can write such embarrassing lines!
Damn!
You're late!
The contract said to be here right after you finish eating dinner, remember?
I just ate dinner!
At my house, dinner is at 7 PM!
Then you should've specified the exact time!
Starting tomorrow, be here on time, okay?
Otherwise, you'll have to pay that million yen penalty!
How to Escape the Hikikomori State
Seminar 2nd Session: Conversation Techniques
In today's seminar, we'll talk about conversation techniques!
Generally, hikikomori people are not good at conversation.
They're not skilled when it comes to having conversations with others,
therefore they tend to choose to seclude themselves even more.
So today, I will teach you brilliant conversation techniques!
Please pay close attention!
You get nervous when you talk to other people.
That's why you stutter or flip out.
And that makes you even more uneasy and you get worse in conversation.
It's a vicious cycle.
So, why do people get nervous?
It is because they don't have confidence in themselves.
They think that other people think they're stupid or look down on them.
They just can't help thinking that way.
So, the fundamental problem is how to have confidence in yourself.
Being confident about yourself...
Frankly, that's not something that can be achieved by through typical measures.
However, I've discovered a revolutionary way to accomplish what was once impossible!
Do you want to know how?
You wanna know, don't you?
Ready for this? It's almost like a Copernican revolution!
In other words, if you can't be confident in yourself,
you just have to regard those around you as being worse than you are!
That's the whole idea.
Huh?
Basically, you look at the person you're conversing with as someone even more pathetic than you.
You just look down on them.
If you do so, you'll be able to smoothly carry on a conversation without getting nervous.
It's quite calming.
You see?
The reason I'm talking with such ease right now is because of this technique!
But you can never let the other person know about it,
because they'll get angry with you.
Even you'd be upset if I called you garbage, or told you that you suck,
or that you're a failure as a human to your face, wouldn't you?
So, I don't tell you.
Hey...
Huh?
So basically, deep down you look down on me as garbage, you think that I suck
and I'm a failure as a human, is that it?
Nope.
That's not true.
You!
Enough about conversation techniques.
Why don't you answer my question from yesterday?
You know, the results of that dream analysis.
Rough-looking snake, apple and gun...
What do they all symbolize?
Sato, you're a virgin, aren't you?
Huh?
You don't even have a girlfriend. I guess you can't help it, huh?
Give me a break!
When I was in high school, my senior and I were...
Well, she wasn't my girlfriend, but...
The guy who lives next to you, Yamazaki, was it?
Even he has a girlfriend.
What? Yamazaki...
You mean that Yamazaki?!
Yeah, your junior, Yamazaki.
The other day, when Auntie Kazuko and I dropped by his place on our recruiting rounds,
he kept going on and on about this girlfriend of his, even though we didn't ask anything about her.
He looked like he was on Cloud Nine.
No way... Him of all guys?!
There's no way he'd be interested in real girls!
Her name is Nanako.
She's a voice-acting student at the same vocational school he goes to.
She has short hair and a slim physique.
She's a little shorter than Yamazaki.
Just as you'd expect from someone who's studying voice-acting, she has a very cute voice, he said.
That's a lie!
If you think it's a lie, why don't you find out for yourself?
Sure, I'll find out!
And I'll expose your lie!
It's pretty simple.
I just have to go straight to his room and ask him for the truth.
Yamazaki! Is that true you have a human girlfriend now?
What are you talking about, Sato?
You know damn well I'd never waste my time on real girls!
My girlfriend is Pururin, and Pururin only!
But it is actually possible that he really does have...
Oops, so you found out, huh?
I'm telling you, 2D girls just can't compare to a real flesh-and-blood girl!
Calm down! I know Yamazaki is the last person who'd do such a thing!
And even if it turns out that he does have one, he'd be like...
None of your business, Sato.
And being told that would piss me off more than anything!
But the real problem here
is that the human is a creature that lies.
Will Yamazaki tell me the truth?
And will I be able to believe the answer?
Sato? What are you doing here?
Oh, I was just passing by. Where are you going?
I'm going to the convenience store real quick.
Wanna come along, Sato?
But I have to, you know, write the script for the game, so...
Okay. Good luck!
Thanks!
I should've just asked!
Big brother, it's morning!
Big Brother, it's morning! You're gonna be late!
In the end, I didn't get a wink of sleep that night.
I guess I just have to see it with my own eyes,
whether he has a girlfriend or not.
If he doesn't have one, then that's okay.
But if she happens to be one of those cute girls found in Shimokitazawa,
I will kill him!
So, this is the school he goes to, huh?
Kokogi Designer Institute
Now that I think about it,
I don't know anything about what he's like at school, do I?
I think he's in the game creation department.
His classroom is...
I don't know!
Then the message for that didn't make it any better! It was straight-up insulting!
It was obvious that the person didn't read the thread at all!
Morning!
Hey!
Last night's Pururin was something else, wasn't it?
Oh yeah! I wonder if that's going to be fixed on the DVDs?
It didn't look like her! It was like, the character was melting!
I bet you there's no executive director of animation working on that thing!
It needs some shading! Is that too much to ask?!
Are you here for the facility tour?
It's supposed be only on Saturdays though.
Oh...
Which courses are you interested in?
Huh? Well, scriptwriting for games.
Really? Then it's perfect!
You should check out my class since you're already here.
Huh?
I'm about to teach my game-writing class.
Today I'd like to review how to draw the human body, using the handouts that I just distributed.
Well, the big difference between female bodies and male bodies is that female bodies are more...
A! E! I! U! E! O! A! O!
A! E! I!
Today I want you to create a project proposal based on what you've learned in yesterday's class.
Listen, I want to see project agendas, who your intended audiences are,
and the genre you're going with.
In game making, the system one uses is also key, so don't forget to cover that area as well.
Surprisingly, the class is a lot more normal than I expected.
It's been three years since I had to do anything like this.
Due to such change in the environment,
Back then I thought I was supposed to keep on going to college for four years until I graduated.
business economics in the 20th century changed;
its primary mission being the contribution
to the effective operation of large-scale firms.
In other words...
Notice of Removal From Register
Student's Name: Tatsuhiro Sato
Student ID #: FR05205
This is to certify the student indicated above has been removed from the school register under the states of Chapter 4, Article 51, Section 2.
Listen!
I want you to write it as if you were going to present it to an actual production company!
The important thing is to be certain to let them know how enthusiastic you are!
All right, let's start!
Name: Tatsuhiro Sato
Game Genre: Ambient-type Gal Game
Target Audience: Young people who are sick of interpersonal relationships
This is an ambient-type gal game, which brings peace into people's heart.
The main character is a charcoal burner, who lives deep in the mountains.
The heroine is the spirit of the mountain.
There are no words spoken between them.
They understand each other without exchanging words.
He burns charcoal in silence for another day while the spirit watches over him.
The spirit is entirely gentle.
She never makes fun of him by calling him a hikikomori.
He has no financial worries or concerns for his future.
Another day, filled with peace and love passes.
Game System: Totally hands-free system!! The very first in the industry! (Possibly)
In addition, this game does not require any complicated gaming techniques.
All a player is required to do is to look at the CG
and the captions that are automatically displayed on the screen.
I hereby would like to submit my proposal for this revolutionary game style.
Hey, hey, you don't have to hide it!
You will never be a respectable creator if you're afraid of having your work seen by others.
It's not like I'm...
I'm sorry for laughing, but I just thought it's a pretty innovative idea.
I was just impressed, that's all.
Don't lie.
Huh?
I know you laughed at me!
Yeah, you look down on me because I'm an amateur.
You think you're all that, huh?
I think I'm "all that" and look down on you, huh?
Listen, everyone's an amateur at the beginning.
But eventually they'll stand on their feet while being made fun of by their teachers and seniors along the way.
Or are you incapable of accepting others unless they're either at or below the same level as you?
If that's the case, the one who's looking down on others is actually you, isn't it?
Basically, you look at the person you're conversing with as someone even more pathetic than you.
You just look down on them.
That's not true... I'm not like that!
You're done already?
I changed it up a little today.
Really? How?
That's a secret!
What? Why do you say that?
What's the matter?
Are they making fun of me?
Is it possible that my reaction gave away the fact that I'm a hikikomori?!
More importantly, what the hell am I doing here?
I'm a hikikomori for god's sake!
Conspiracy...
That's right, this is a conspiracy.
It's an evil secret organization that's been following me!
This is a conspiracy plotted by the Nihon Hikikomori Kyokai!
H-Hey!
What am I doing?
Who gives a damn about Yamazaki's girlfriend anyway!
I came all the way to a busy place like this all by myself.
How am I gonna get home now?
What am I supposed to do?
Okay, I'll be waiting for you in the break room!
Hey, Nanako!
Yamazaki?!
Seriously! This masterpiece will make history!
Really? Are you sure about that?
I'm telling you, it's the most interesting game without a doubt!
You should definitely play it too, Nanako!
Nanako?
So, that's Yamazaki's girlfriend?
But rumor has it that it's an obvious knock-off.
I'm not sure about a game like that.
Damn, she's cute! You son of a bitch!
After he dragged me into the world of 2D,
he gets himself a flesh-and-blood chick?!
Unforgivable!
The sentence has now been passed down!
Death!
Tonight, Mita House will be covered in blood!
Then I'll bring it tomorrow, so you can check it out for yourself!
Nanako!
Sorry to keep you waiting!
Let's go home, Nanako! Come on!
Well then, Yamazaki.
See you tomorrow.
O-Okay...
See you tomorrow!
You guys are so lovey-dovey as usual!
Like he's your boyfriend or something!
Hey, stop it!
There's no way I'd go out with Yamazaki!
He's just a friend.
You're right.
He doesn't look that bad, but he's a creepy otaku!
He's like half "hikky" anyway.
He looks like he's into little girls too!
Ewwww!
First of all, right now, I'm crazy about Kazuo anyway!
Sato?
Yamazaki, I saw it!
Huh?
Really? I can't believe you saw that!
Her name is Nanako Midorikawa.
She's a voice-acting student!
We started dating about two weeks ago.
Man, she's pretty hot.
Isn't she?! Supposedly some other guys were also after her,
but in the end, she chose me to be her boyfriend!
You're a lucky bastard, you know that?
But she doesn't think of you as...
I'm telling you! There's nothing like a real girl!
They're the best!
I see. Just like I thought, she wasn't his girlfriend after all, huh?
Yeah, he just thinks she is.
"Just like you thought"? So, you were...
Yeah, I kinda suspected that.
You have no idea what I went through!
I followed Yamazaki and even managed to get inside his school!
But you know what?
You, a hikikomori, actually went to a place with lots of people.
That's progress, I'd say!
Right?
Hey, was this her goal all along?!
Owww...
I landed on my butt...
Episode 06
Welcome to the Classroom!
Yeah, right.
Ababa, ababa, ababa, dancing baby human!
ababa ababa ababa odoru akachan ningen hogya
When we were born naked,
hito wa hadaka de umareta toki wa
we were all loved equally, just as it's supposed to be.
dare mo aisare onajina hazu ga
But why, as life goes on,
doushite nano da ikite iku uchi
does each destiny take a different path? It's almost cruel.
sadame wa wakare mugoi kurai da
Some can look at other's eyes, while others can't.
hito no me mitari mirenakattari
Some get to learn love, while others don't.
koi wo shittari shirenakattari
If that's how it is, I'd rather be
sore nara boku wa isso naritai
a baby, a baby human till I die.
shinu made baby akachan ningen
"Oh, what an adorable baby!"
Ah, nante kawaii baby
"I just want to love you!"
aishitaku naru wa
(Just like I planned!)
omou tsubo daze
(It worked perfectly!)
umaku ittaze
The baby she's holding isn't really a baby human.
kanojo daita akago jitsu wa akachan ningen
"Ababa!" I snicker to myself, hiding in my pretended innocence.
adokenasa no ura de ababa hokusoemu no sa
It's so easy to be a baby human, so you should be one too!
kimi mo nare yo raku de iize baby human
Ababa, ababa! Dance, multiply, and take it to space!
ababa ababa odore fuyase soshite uchuu e
To Mars! To Saturn! To the galaxy! Dance! Baby human!
kasei e dosei e ginga e odoru yo akachan ningen
Dance! Baby human!
odoru yo akachan ningen
NEET isn't just my title!
Hello there, I'm Kaoru Yamazaki!
Do you want me to pretend to be your girlfriend?
Next Episode
Welcome to the Moratorium!
Next episode, "Welcome to the Moratorium!"